{
     "title": "/Chapter 15/Monopoly",
     "icon": "<svg xmlns=\"http://www.w3.org/2000/svg\" class=\"h-8 w-8\" fill=\"none\" viewBox=\"0 0 24 24\" stroke=\"currentColor\" stroke-width=\"2\"><path stroke-linecap=\"round\" stroke-linejoin=\"round\" d=\"M19 11H5m14 0a2 2 0 012 2v6a2 2 0 01-2 2H5a2 2 0 01-2-2v-6a2 2 0 012-2m14 0V9a2 2 0 00-2-2M5 11V9a2 2 0 012-2m0 0V5a2 2 0 012-2h6a2 2 0 012 2v2M7 7h10\" /></svg>",
     "sectors": {
          "sector1": {
               "title": "MULTIPLE CHOICE",
               "questions": [
                    {
                         "q_num": 1,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "Both a competitive firm and a monopolist are price takers.",
                              "Both a competitive firm and a monopolist are price makers.",
                              "A competitive firm is a price taker, whereas a monopolist is a price maker.",
                              "A competitive firm is a price maker, whereas a monopolist is a price taker."
                         ],
                         "answer": "A competitive firm is a price taker, whereas a monopolist is a price maker.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 2,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "One difference between a perfectly competitive firm and a monopoly is that a perfectly competitive firm produces where",
                         "options": [
                              "marginal cost equals price, while a monopolist produces where price exceeds marginal cost.",
                              "marginal cost equals price, while a monopolist produces where marginal cost exceeds price.",
                              "price exceeds marginal cost, while a monopolist produces where marginal cost equals price.",
                              "marginal cost exceeds price, while a monopolist produces where marginal cost equals price."
                         ],
                         "answer": "marginal cost equals price, while a monopolist produces where price exceeds marginal cost.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 3,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopoly",
                         "options": [
                              "can set the price it charges for its output and earn unlimited profits.",
                              "takes the market price as given and earns small but positive profits.",
                              "can set the price it charges for its output but faces a downward-sloping demand curve so it cannot earn unlimited profits.",
                              "can set the price it charges for its output but faces a horizontal demand curve so it can earn unlimited profits."
                         ],
                         "answer": "can set the price it charges for its output but faces a downward-sloping demand curve so it cannot earn unlimited profits.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 4,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A perfectly competitive market",
                         "options": [
                              "may not be in the best interests of society, whereas a monopoly market promotes general economic well-being",
                              "promotes general economic well-being, whereas a monopoly market may not be in the best interests of society.",
                              "and a monopoly market are equally likely to promote general economic well-being.",
                              "is less likely to promote general economic well-being than a monopoly market."
                         ],
                         "answer": "promotes general economic well-being, whereas a monopoly market may not be in the best interests of society.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 5,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Because monopoly firms do not have to compete with other firms, the outcome in a market with a monopoly is often",
                         "options": [
                              "not in the best interest of society.",
                              "one that fails to maximize total economic well-being.",
                              "inefficient.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 6,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Because a monopolist does not face competition from other firms, the outcome in a market with a monopoly",
                         "options": [
                              "does not illustrate profit maximization.",
                              "is often not in the best interest of society.",
                              "is characterized by unlimited profits.",
                              "would be improved if the government produced the product rather than a private firm."
                         ],
                         "answer": "is often not in the best interest of society.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 7,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Microsoft faces very little competition from other firms for its Windows software. Why isn’t the price of the software $1,000 per copy?",
                         "options": [
                              "because the government would not allow such a high price",
                              "because stockholders would not allow such a high price",
                              "because the company would sell so few copies that they would earn higher profits by selling at a lower price",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "because the company would sell so few copies that they would earn higher profits by selling at a lower price",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 8,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The DeBeers company faces very little competition from other firms in the wholesale diamond market. Why isn’t the price of the wholesale diamonds $10,000 per carat?",
                         "options": [
                              "because the government would not allow such a high price",
                              "because stockholders would not allow such a high price",
                              "because the company would sell so few copies that they would earn higher profits by selling at a lower price",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "because the company would sell so few copies that they would earn higher profits by selling at a lower price",
                         "explanation": ""
                    }
               ]
          },
          "sector2": {
               "title": "WHY MONOPOLIES ARISE",
               "questions": [
                    {
                         "q_num": 1,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of a monopoly?",
                         "options": [
                              "barriers to entry",
                              "one seller",
                              "one buyer",
                              "a product without close substitutes"
                         ],
                         "answer": "one buyer",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 3,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The fundamental source of monopoly power is",
                         "options": [
                              "barriers to entry.",
                              "profit.",
                              "decreasing average total cost.",
                              "a product without close substitutes."
                         ],
                         "answer": "barriers to entry.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 7,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following are necessary characteristics of a monopoly?\n(i),The firm is the sole seller of its product.\n(ii),The firm's product does not have close substitutes.\n(iii),The firm generates a large economic profit.\n(iv),The firm is located in a small geographic market.",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(i) and (iii) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), and (iii) only\"",
                              "\"(i), (ii), (iii), and (iv)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "(i) and (ii) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 11,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following would be most likely to have monopoly power?",
                         "options": [
                              "a long-distance telephone service provider",
                              "a local cable TV provider",
                              "a large department store",
                              "a gas station"
                         ],
                         "answer": "a local cable TV provider",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 16,
                         "topic": "Barriers to entry",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following is not an example of a barrier to entry?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"Mighty Mitch’s Mining Company owns a unique plot of land in Tanzania, under which lies the only large deposit of Tanzanite in the world.\"",
                              "A pharmaceutical company obtains a patent for a specific high blood pressure medication.",
                              "A musician obtains a copyright for her original song.",
                              "An entrepreneur opens a popular new restaurant."
                         ],
                         "answer": "An entrepreneur opens a popular new restaurant.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 22,
                         "topic": "Barriers to entry",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following is an example of a barrier to entry?\n(i),A key resource is owned by a single firm.\n(ii),The costs of production make a single producer more efficient than a large number of producers.\n(iii),The government has given the existing monopolist the exclusive right to produce the good.",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(ii) and (iii) only",
                              "(i) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 28,
                         "topic": "Patents | Copyrights",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Patent and copyright laws are major sources of",
                         "options": [
                              "natural monopolies.",
                              "government-created monopolies.",
                              "resource monopolies.",
                              "antitrust regulation."
                         ],
                         "answer": "government-created monopolies.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 33,
                         "topic": "Patents | Copyrights",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A benefit to society of the patent and copyright laws is that those laws",
                         "options": [
                              "help to keep prices down.",
                              "help to prevent a single firm from acquiring ownership of a key resource.",
                              "encourage creative activity.",
                              "discourage the production of inefficient products."
                         ],
                         "answer": "encourage creative activity.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 40,
                         "topic": "Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-1. The shape of the average total cost curve reveals information about the nature of the barrier to entry that might exist in a monopoly market. Which of the following monopoly types best coincides with the figure?",
                         "options": [
                              "ownership of a key resource by a single firm",
                              "natural monopoly",
                              "government-created monopoly",
                              "a patent or copyright monopoly"
                         ],
                         "answer": "natural monopoly",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 45,
                         "topic": "Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-1: Consider a transportation corporation named C.R. Evans that has just completed the development of a new subway system in a medium-sized town in the Northwest. Currently, there are plenty of seats on the subway, and it is never crowded. Its capacity far exceeds the needs of the city. After just a few years of operation, the shareholders of C.R. Evans experienced incredible rates of return on their investment due to the profitability of the corporation.\n\nRefer to Scenario 15-1. Which of the following statements is most likely to be true?\n(i),New entrants to the market know they will have a smaller market share than C.R. Evans currently has.\n(ii),C.R. Evans is most likely experiencing decreasing average total cost.\n(iii),C.R. Evans is a natural monopoly.",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(ii) and (iii) only",
                              "(i) and (iii) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 54,
                         "topic": "Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The defining characteristic of a natural monopoly is",
                         "options": [
                              "constant marginal cost over the relevant range of output.",
                              "economies of scale over the relevant range of output.",
                              "constant returns to scale over the relevant range of output.",
                              "diseconomies of scale over the relevant range of output."
                         ],
                         "answer": "economies of scale over the relevant range of output.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 66,
                         "topic": "Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If government officials break a natural monopoly up into several smaller firms, then",
                         "options": [
                              "competition will force firms to attain economic profits rather than accounting profits.",
                              "\"competition will force firms to produce surplus output, which drives up price.\"",
                              "the average costs of production will increase.",
                              "the average costs of production will decrease."
                         ],
                         "answer": "the average costs of production will increase.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    }
               ]
          },
          "sector3": {
               "title": "HOW MONOPOLIES MAKE PRODUCTION AND PRICING DECISIONS",
               "questions": [
                    {
                         "q_num": 1,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is (are) true of a monopoly?\n(i),A monopoly has the ability to set the price of its product at whatever level it desires.\n(ii),A monopoly's total revenue will always increase when it increases the price of its product.\n(iii),A monopoly can earn unlimited profits.",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) only",
                              "(ii) only",
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(ii) and (iii) only"
                         ],
                         "answer": "(i) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 2,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Amanda inherited the only local cable TV company in town after her father passed away. The company is completely unregulated by the government and is therefore free to operate as it wishes. Assume that Amanda understands the true power of her new monopoly. Which of the following statements is (are) correct?\n(i),She will be able to set the price of cable TV service at whatever level she wishes.\n(ii),The customers will be forced to purchase cable TV service at whatever price she wants to set.\n(iii),She will be able to achieve any profit level that she desires.",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) only",
                              "(ii) only",
                              "(i) and (iii) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "(i) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 3,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The market demand curve for a monopolist is typically",
                         "options": [
                              "unit price elastic.",
                              "downward sloping.",
                              "horizontal.",
                              "vertical."
                         ],
                         "answer": "downward sloping.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 4,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "When a firm operates under conditions of monopoly, its price is",
                         "options": [
                              "not constrained.",
                              "constrained by marginal cost.",
                              "constrained by demand.",
                              "constrained only by its social agenda."
                         ],
                         "answer": "constrained by demand.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 5,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "In order to sell more of its product, a monopolist must",
                         "options": [
                              "sell to the government.",
                              "sell in international markets.",
                              "lower its price.",
                              "use its market power to force up the price of complementary products."
                         ],
                         "answer": "lower its price.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 6,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "In order to sell more of its product, a monopolist must",
                         "options": [
                              "lobby the government for a subsidy.",
                              "lower its price.",
                              "advertise.",
                              "enact barriers to entry in related markets."
                         ],
                         "answer": "lower its price.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 7,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Economists assume that monopolists behave as",
                         "options": [
                              "cost minimizers.",
                              "profit maximizers.",
                              "price maximizers.",
                              "maximizers of social welfare."
                         ],
                         "answer": "profit maximizers.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 8,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Because a monopolist is the sole producer in its market, it can necessarily alter the price of its good\n(i),without affecting the quantity sold.\n(ii),without affecting its average total cost.\n(iii),by adjusting the quantity it supplies to the market.",
                         "options": [
                              "(ii) only",
                              "(iii) only",
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(ii) and (iii) only"
                         ],
                         "answer": "(iii) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 9,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "When a monopolist decreases the price of its good, consumers",
                         "options": [
                              "continue to buy the same amount.",
                              "buy more.",
                              "buy less.",
                              "\"may buy more or less, depending on the price elasticity of demand.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "buy more.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 10,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "When a monopolist increases the amount of output that it produces and sells, the price of its output",
                         "options": [
                              "stays the same.",
                              "increases.",
                              "decreases.",
                              "may increase or decrease depending on the price elasticity of demand."
                         ],
                         "answer": "decreases.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 11,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopoly firm is a price",
                         "options": [
                              "taker and has no supply curve.",
                              "maker and has no supply curve",
                              "taker and has an upward-sloping supply curve.",
                              "maker and has an upward-sloping supply curve."
                         ],
                         "answer": "maker and has no supply curve",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 12,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Monopolies use their market power to",
                         "options": [
                              "charge prices that equal minimum average total cost.",
                              "increase the quantity sold as they increase price.",
                              "charge a price that is higher than marginal cost.",
                              "dump excess supplies of their product on the market."
                         ],
                         "answer": "charge a price that is higher than marginal cost.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 13,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Monopoly firms have",
                         "options": [
                              "\"downward-sloping demand curves, and they can sell as much output as they desire at the market price.\"",
                              "\"downward-sloping demand curves, and they can sell only a limited quantity of output at each price.\"",
                              "\"horizontal demand curves, and they can sell as much output as they desire at the market price.\"",
                              "\"horizontal demand curves, and they can sell only a limited quantity of output at each price.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"downward-sloping demand curves, and they can sell only a limited quantity of output at each price.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 14,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following is not correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "The demand curve facing a competitive firm is perfectly elastic.",
                              "The demand curve facing a monopolist is the market demand curve.",
                              "A monopolist can charge any price and sell any quantity that it chooses.",
                              "A monopolist can alter the market price by adjusting the quantity that it produces."
                         ],
                         "answer": "A monopolist can charge any price and sell any quantity that it chooses.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 15,
                         "topic": "Monopoly | Perfect competition",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"The demand curve facing a competitive firm is horizontal, as is the demand curve facing a monopolist.\"",
                              "\"The demand curve facing a competitive firm is downward sloping, whereas the demand curve facing a monopolist is horizontal.\"",
                              "\"The demand curve facing a competitive firm is horizontal, whereas the demand curve facing a monopolist is downward sloping.\"",
                              "\"The demand curve facing a competitive firm is downward sloping, as is the demand curve facing a monopolist.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"The demand curve facing a competitive firm is horizontal, whereas the demand curve facing a monopolist is downward sloping.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 16,
                         "topic": "Monopoly | Perfect competition",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The profit-maximization problem for a monopolist differs from that of a competitive firm in which of the following ways?",
                         "options": [
                              "A competitive firm maximizes profit at the point where marginal revenue equals marginal cost; a monopolist maximizes profit at the point where marginal revenue exceeds marginal cost.",
                              "A competitive firm maximizes profit at the point where average revenue equals marginal cost; a monopolist maximizes profit at the point where average revenue exceeds marginal cost.",
                              "\"For a competitive firm, marginal revenue at the profit-maximizing level of output is equal to marginal revenue at all other levels of output; for a monopolist, marginal revenue at the profit-maximizing level of output is smaller than it is for larger levels of output.\"",
                              "\"For a profit-maximizing competitive firm, thinking at the margin is much more important than it is for a profit-maximizing monopolist.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "A competitive firm maximizes profit at the point where average revenue equals marginal cost; a monopolist maximizes profit at the point where average revenue exceeds marginal cost.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 17,
                         "topic": "Perfect competition | Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Competitive firms differ from monopolies in which of the following ways?\n(i),Competitive firms do not have to worry about the price effect lowering their total revenue.\n(ii),\"Marginal revenue for a competitive firm equals price, while marginal revenue for a monopoly is less than the price it is able to charge.\"\n(iii),\"Monopolies must lower their price in order to sell more of their product, while competitive firms do not.\"",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(ii) and (iii) only",
                              "(i) and (iii) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 18,
                         "topic": "Perfect competition",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Competitive firms have",
                         "options": [
                              "\"downward-sloping demand curves, and they can sell as much output as they desire at the market price.\"",
                              "\"downward-sloping demand curves, and they can sell only a limited quantity of output at each price.\"",
                              "\"horizontal demand curves, and they can sell as much output as they desire at the market price.\"",
                              "\"horizontal demand curves, and they can sell only a limited quantity of output at each price.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"horizontal demand curves, and they can sell as much output as they desire at the market price.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 19,
                         "topic": "Perfect competition",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Because many good substitutes exist for a competitive firm's product, the demand curve that it faces is",
                         "options": [
                              "unit-elastic.",
                              "perfectly inelastic.",
                              "perfectly elastic.",
                              "inelastic only over a certain region."
                         ],
                         "answer": "perfectly elastic.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 20,
                         "topic": "Demand curve",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "In a market characterized by monopoly, the market demand curve is",
                         "options": [
                              "upward sloping.",
                              "horizontal.",
                              "downward sloping.",
                              "vertical."
                         ],
                         "answer": "downward sloping.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 21,
                         "topic": "Demand curve",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "As a monopolist increases the quantity of output it sells, the price consumers are willing to pay for the good",
                         "options": [
                              "is unaffected.",
                              "decreases.",
                              "increases.",
                              "There is not enough information given in answer the question."
                         ],
                         "answer": "decreases.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 22,
                         "topic": "Demand curve",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Suppose a firm has a monopoly on the sale of widgets and faces a downward-sloping demand curve. When selling the 100th widget, the firm will always receive",
                         "options": [
                              "less marginal revenue on the 100th widget than it received on the 99th widget.",
                              "more average revenue on the 100th widget than it received on the 99th widget.",
                              "more total revenue on the 100 widgets than it received on the first 99 widgets.",
                              "a lower average cost per unit at 100 units output than at 99 units of output."
                         ],
                         "answer": "less marginal revenue on the 100th widget than it received on the 99th widget.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 23,
                         "topic": "Demand curve",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Suppose a firm has a monopoly on the sale of a computer game and faces a downward-sloping demand curve. When selling the 50th game, the firm will always receive",
                         "options": [
                              "less marginal revenue on the 50th game than it received on the 49th game.",
                              "more average revenue on the 50th game than it received on the 49th game.",
                              "more total revenue on the 50 game than it received on the first 49 game.",
                              "Both b) and c) are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "less marginal revenue on the 50th game than it received on the 49th game.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 24,
                         "topic": "Demand curve | Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a monopoly firm, the shape and position of the demand curve play a role in determining the\n(i),profit-maximizing price.\n(ii),shape and position of the marginal-cost curve.\n(iii),shape and position of the marginal-revenue curve.",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(ii) and (iii) only",
                              "(i) and (iii) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "(i) and (iii) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 25,
                         "topic": "Total revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a monopoly, the level of output at which marginal revenue equals zero is also the level of output at which",
                         "options": [
                              "average revenue is zero.",
                              "profit is maximized.",
                              "total revenue is maximized.",
                              "marginal cost is zero."
                         ],
                         "answer": "total revenue is maximized.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 26,
                         "topic": "Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopolist's average revenue is always",
                         "options": [
                              "equal to marginal revenue.",
                              "greater than the price of its product.",
                              "equal to the price of its product.",
                              "less than the price of its product."
                         ],
                         "answer": "equal to the price of its product.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 27,
                         "topic": "Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If a profit-maximizing monopolist faces a downward-sloping market demand curve, its",
                         "options": [
                              "average revenue is less than the price of the product.",
                              "average revenue is less than marginal revenue.",
                              "marginal revenue is less than the price of the product.",
                              "marginal revenue is greater than the price of the product."
                         ],
                         "answer": "marginal revenue is less than the price of the product.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 28,
                         "topic": "Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "When a monopolist increases the amount of output that it produces and sells, average revenue",
                         "options": [
                              "\"increases, and marginal revenue increases.\"",
                              "\"increases, and marginal revenue decreases.\"",
                              "\"decreases, and marginal revenue increases.\"",
                              "\"decreases, and marginal revenue decreases.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"decreases, and marginal revenue decreases.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 29,
                         "topic": "Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a monopoly firm, which of the following equalities is always true?",
                         "options": [
                              "price = marginal revenue",
                              "price = average revenue",
                              "price = total revenue",
                              "marginal revenue = marginal cost"
                         ],
                         "answer": "price = average revenue",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 30,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue | Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is correct for a monopolist?\ni),The firm maximizes profits by equating marginal revenue with marginal cost.\nii),The firm maximizes profits by equating price with marginal cost.\niii),Demand equals marginal revenue.\niv),Average revenue equals price.",
                         "options": [
                              "\"i), iii), and iv) only\"",
                              "i) and iv) only",
                              "\"i), ii), and iv) only\"",
                              "\"i), ii), iii), and iv)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "i) and iv) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 31,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue | Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is correct for both a monopolist and a perfectly competitive firm?\ni),The firm maximizes profits by equating marginal revenue with marginal cost.\nii),The firm maximizes profits by equating price with marginal cost.\niii),Demand equals marginal revenue.\niv),Average revenue equals price.",
                         "options": [
                              "\"i), iii), and iv) only\"",
                              "i) and iv) only",
                              "\"i), ii), and iv) only\"",
                              "\"i), ii), iii), and iv)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "i) and iv) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 32,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue | Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is true?\n(i),\"When a competitive firm sells an additional unit of output, its revenue increases by an amount less than the price.\"\n(ii),\"When a monopoly firm sells an additional unit of output, its revenue increases by an amount less than the price.\"\n(iii),Average revenue is the same as price for both competitive and monopoly firms.",
                         "options": [
                              "(ii) only",
                              "(iii) only",
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(ii) and (iii) only"
                         ],
                         "answer": "(ii) and (iii) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 33,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue | Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The marginal revenue curve for a monopoly firm starts at the same point on the vertical axis as the\n(i),average revenue curve.\n(ii),marginal cost curve.\n(iii),demand curve.",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) only",
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(i) and (iii) only",
                              "(iii) only"
                         ],
                         "answer": "(i) and (iii) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 34,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue | Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a monopoly,",
                         "options": [
                              "average revenue exceeds marginal revenue.",
                              "average revenue equals marginal revenue.",
                              "average revenue is less than marginal revenue.",
                              "price equals marginal revenue."
                         ],
                         "answer": "average revenue exceeds marginal revenue.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 35,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue | Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a monopolist, when does marginal revenue exceed average revenue?",
                         "options": [
                              "never",
                              "when output is less than the profit-maximizing level of output",
                              "when output is greater than the profit-maximizing level of output",
                              "for all levels of output greater than zero"
                         ],
                         "answer": "never",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 36,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Because a monopolist must lower its price in order to sell another unit of output,",
                         "options": [
                              "marginal revenue is less than price.",
                              "long-term economic profits will be zero.",
                              "total revenue increases as price increases.",
                              "average revenue is less than price."
                         ],
                         "answer": "marginal revenue is less than price.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 37,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "What is the shape of the monopolist’s marginal revenue curve?",
                         "options": [
                              "a downward-sloping line that is identical to the demand curve",
                              "a downward-sloping line that lies below the demand curve",
                              "a horizontal line that is identical to the demand curve",
                              "a horizontal line that lies below the demand curve"
                         ],
                         "answer": "a downward-sloping line that lies below the demand curve",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 38,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a monopolist, marginal revenue is",
                         "options": [
                              "\"equal to price, as it is for a perfectly competitive firm.\"",
                              "\"less than price, as it is for a perfectly competitive firm.\"",
                              "\"equal to price, whereas marginal revenue is less than price for a perfectly competitive firm.\"",
                              "\"less than price, whereas marginal revenue is equal to price for a perfectly competitive firm.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"less than price, whereas marginal revenue is equal to price for a perfectly competitive firm.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 39,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "When a monopolist increases the number of units it sells, there are two effects on revenue. They are the",
                         "options": [
                              "demand effect and the supply effect.",
                              "competition effect and the cost effect.",
                              "competitive effect and the monopoly effect.",
                              "output effect and the price effect."
                         ],
                         "answer": "output effect and the price effect.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 40,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a monopolist, marginal revenue is",
                         "options": [
                              "positive when the demand effect is greater than the supply effect.",
                              "positive when the monopoly effect is greater than the competitive effect.",
                              "negative when the price effect is greater than the output effect.",
                              "negative when the output effect is greater than the price effect."
                         ],
                         "answer": "negative when the price effect is greater than the output effect.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 41,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a monopolist, when the price effect is greater than the output effect, marginal revenue is",
                         "options": [
                              "positive.",
                              "negative.",
                              "zero.",
                              "maximized."
                         ],
                         "answer": "negative.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 42,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a monopolist, when the output effect is greater than the price effect, marginal revenue is",
                         "options": [
                              "positive.",
                              "negative.",
                              "zero.",
                              "maximized."
                         ],
                         "answer": "positive.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 43,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "When a monopoly increases its output and sales,",
                         "options": [
                              "both the output effect and the price effect work to increase total revenue.",
                              "\"the output effect works to increase total revenue, and the price effect works to decrease total revenue.\"",
                              "\"the output effect works to decrease total revenue, and the price effect works to increase total revenue.\"",
                              "both the output effect and the price effect work to decrease total revenue."
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"the output effect works to increase total revenue, and the price effect works to decrease total revenue.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 44,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Marginal revenue for a monopolist is computed as",
                         "options": [
                              "average revenue divided by quantity sold.",
                              "average revenue times quantity divided by price.",
                              "total revenue divided by quantity sold.",
                              "change in total revenue per one unit increase in quantity sold."
                         ],
                         "answer": "change in total revenue per one unit increase in quantity sold.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 45,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Marginal revenue can become negative for",
                         "options": [
                              "both competitive and monopoly firms.",
                              "competitive firms but not for monopoly firms.",
                              "monopoly firms but not for competitive firms.",
                              "neither competitive nor monopoly firms."
                         ],
                         "answer": "monopoly firms but not for competitive firms.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 46,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a monopolist,",
                         "options": [
                              "average revenue is always greater than the price of the good.",
                              "marginal revenue is always less than the price of the good.",
                              "marginal cost is always greater than average total cost.",
                              "marginal revenue equals marginal cost at the point where total revenue is maximized."
                         ],
                         "answer": "marginal revenue is always less than the price of the good.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 47,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If a monopoly lowers its price, its",
                         "options": [
                              "total revenue must increase.",
                              "total revenue must decrease.",
                              "marginal revenue must increase.",
                              "marginal revenue must decrease."
                         ],
                         "answer": "marginal revenue must decrease.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 48,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "With no price discrimination, the monopolist sells every unit at the same price. Therefore",
                         "options": [
                              "marginal revenue is equal to price.",
                              "marginal revenue is equal to average revenue.",
                              "price is greater than marginal revenue.",
                              "Both a and b are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "price is greater than marginal revenue.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 49,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopolist can sell 200 units of output for $36 per unit. Alternatively, it can sell 201 units of output for $35.80 per unit. The marginal revenue of the 201st unit of output is",
                         "options": [
                              "$-4.20.",
                              "$-0.20.",
                              "$4.20.",
                              "$35.80."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$-4.20.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 50,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopoly firm can sell 150 units of output for $10 per unit. Alternatively, it can sell 151 units of output for $9.95 per unit. The marginal revenue of the 151st unit of output is",
                         "options": [
                              "$-2.45.",
                              "$-0.05.",
                              "$2.45.",
                              "$9.95."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$2.45.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 51,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "When a certain monopoly sets its price at $8 it sells 64 units. When the monopoly sets its price at $10 it sells 60 units. The marginal revenue for the firm over this range is",
                         "options": [
                              "$11.",
                              "$22.",
                              "$33.",
                              "$44."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$22.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 52,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If a monopolist can sell 7 units when the price is $4 and 8 units when the price is $3, then marginal revenue of selling the eighth unit is equal to",
                         "options": [
                              "$3.",
                              "$4.",
                              "$24.",
                              "-$4."
                         ],
                         "answer": "-$4.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 53,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If the monopolist’s linear demand curve intersects the quantity axis at Q = 30, then the monopolist’s marginal revenue will be equal to zero at",
                         "options": [
                              "Q = 10.",
                              "Q = 15.",
                              "Q = 20.",
                              "Q = 30."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Q = 15.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 54,
                         "topic": "Pricing",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Angelo is a wholesale meatball distributor. He sells his meatballs to all the finest Italian restaurants in town. Nobody can make meatballs like Angelo. As a result, his is the only business in town that sells meatballs to restaurants. Assuming that Angelo is maximizing his profit, which of the following statements is true?",
                         "options": [
                              "Meatball prices will be less than marginal cost.",
                              "Meatball prices will equal marginal cost.",
                              "Meatball prices will exceed marginal cost.",
                              "Costs are irrelevant to Angelo because he is a monopolist."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Meatball prices will exceed marginal cost.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 55,
                         "topic": "Pricing",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If a monopolist's marginal costs increase by $1 for all levels of output, then the monopoly price will",
                         "options": [
                              "rise by $1.",
                              "rise by more than $1.",
                              "rise by less than $1.",
                              "\"not change, but profits will decrease.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "rise by less than $1.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 56,
                         "topic": "Pricing",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If a monopolist has zero marginal costs, it will produce",
                         "options": [
                              "the output at which total revenue is maximized.",
                              "in the range in which marginal revenue is still increasing.",
                              "at the point at which marginal revenue is at a maximum.",
                              "in the range in which marginal revenue is negative."
                         ],
                         "answer": "the output at which total revenue is maximized.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 57,
                         "topic": "Monopoly | Perfect competition",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-2. Which of the following statements is correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"Panel C represents the typical demand curve for a perfectly competitive firm, and Panel B represents the typical demand curve for a monopoly.\"",
                              "\"Panel B represents the typical demand curve for a perfectly competitive firm, and Panel C represents the typical demand curve for a monopoly.\"",
                              "\"Panel A represents the typical demand curve for a perfectly competitive firm, and Panel B represents the typical demand curve for a monopoly.\"",
                              "\"Panel C represents the typical demand curve for a perfectly competitive firm, and Panel D represents the typical demand curve for a monopoly.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"Panel C represents the typical demand curve for a perfectly competitive firm, and Panel B represents the typical demand curve for a monopoly.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 58,
                         "topic": "Monopoly | Perfect competition",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-2. Which of the following statements is correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "Panel C represents the typical demand curve for a perfectly competitive firm.",
                              "Panel B represents the typical demand curve for a monopoly.",
                              "Panel B represents the typical demand curve for a perfectly competitive industry.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 59,
                         "topic": "Monopoly | Perfect competition",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-2. Which of the following statements is correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "Panel C represents the typical demand curve for a perfectly competitive industry.",
                              "Panel B represents the typical demand curve for a monopoly.",
                              "Panel B represents the typical demand curve for a perfectly competitive firm.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Panel B represents the typical demand curve for a monopoly.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 60,
                         "topic": "Monopoly | Perfect competition",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-2. Which panel could represent the demand curve facing a soybean farmer?",
                         "options": [
                              "Panel A",
                              "Panel B",
                              "Panel C",
                              "Panel D"
                         ],
                         "answer": "Panel C",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 61,
                         "topic": "Monopoly  | Perfect competition",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-2. Which panel could represent the demand curve facing the soybean industry?",
                         "options": [
                              "Panel A",
                              "Panel B",
                              "Panel C",
                              "Panel D"
                         ],
                         "answer": "Panel B",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 62,
                         "topic": "Monopoly  | Perfect competition",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-2. Which panel could represent the demand curve facing a local cable television provider if that firm in a monopolist?",
                         "options": [
                              "Panel A",
                              "Panel B",
                              "Panel C",
                              "Panel D"
                         ],
                         "answer": "Panel B",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 63,
                         "topic": "Demand curve",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-3 . The demand curve for a monopoly firm is depicted by curve",
                         "options": [
                              "A.",
                              "B.",
                              "C.",
                              "D."
                         ],
                         "answer": "A.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 64,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-3 . The marginal revenue curve for a monopoly firm is depicted by curve",
                         "options": [
                              "A.",
                              "B.",
                              "C.",
                              "D."
                         ],
                         "answer": "B.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 65,
                         "topic": "Marginal cost",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-3 . The marginal cost curve for a monopoly firm is depicted by curve",
                         "options": [
                              "A.",
                              "B.",
                              "C.",
                              "D."
                         ],
                         "answer": "C.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 66,
                         "topic": "Average total cost",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-3 . The average total cost curve for a monopoly firm is depicted by curve",
                         "options": [
                              "A.",
                              "B.",
                              "C.",
                              "D."
                         ],
                         "answer": "D.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 67,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-3 . If the monopoly firm is currently producing Q3 units of output, then a decrease in output will necessarily cause profit to",
                         "options": [
                              "remain unchanged.",
                              "decrease.",
                              "increase as long as the new level of output is at least Q2.",
                              "increase as long as the new level of output is at least Q1."
                         ],
                         "answer": "increase as long as the new level of output is at least Q2.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 68,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-3 . Profit can always be increased by increasing the level of output by one unit if the monopolist is currently operating at\n(i) Q0.\n(ii) Q1.\n(iii) Q2.\n(iv) Q3.",
                         "options": [
                              "(ii) only",
                              "(i) or (ii) only",
                              "(i) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), or (iii) only\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "(i) or (ii) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 69,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-3 . If the monopoly firm wants to maximize its profit, it should operate at a level of output equal to",
                         "options": [
                              "Q1.",
                              "Q2.",
                              "Q3.",
                              "Q4."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Q2.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 70,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-3 . Profit will be maximized by charging a price equal to",
                         "options": [
                              "P1.",
                              "P2.",
                              "P3.",
                              "P4."
                         ],
                         "answer": "P4.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 71,
                         "topic": "Total revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-3 . A profit-maximizing monopoly's total revenue is equal to",
                         "options": [
                              "P4 x Q2.",
                              "P3 x Q4.",
                              "(P4-P2) x Q2.",
                              "(P4-P3) x Q2."
                         ],
                         "answer": "P4 x Q2.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 72,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-4 . A profit-maximizing monopoly will produce an output level of",
                         "options": [
                              "Q1.",
                              "Q2.",
                              "Q3.",
                              "Q4."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Q3.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 73,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-4 . A profit-maximizing monopoly will charge a price of",
                         "options": [
                              "P5.",
                              "P4.",
                              "P3.",
                              "P2."
                         ],
                         "answer": "P4.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 74,
                         "topic": "Total revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-4 . A profit-maximizing monopoly's total revenue is equal to",
                         "options": [
                              "P4 x Q3.",
                              "P5 x Q1.",
                              "P3  x Q4.",
                              "(P4-P2) x Q3."
                         ],
                         "answer": "P4 x Q3.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 75,
                         "topic": "Total cost",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-4 . A profit-maximizing monopoly's total cost is equal to",
                         "options": [
                              "P4 x Q3.",
                              "P2 x Q3.",
                              "P1 x Q3.",
                              "(P4-P1) x Q3."
                         ],
                         "answer": "P1 x Q3.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 76,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-4 . A profit-maximizing monopoly's profit is equal to",
                         "options": [
                              "P4 x Q3.",
                              "(P4-P2) x Q3.",
                              "(P4-P1) x Q3.",
                              "(P5-P0) x Q1."
                         ],
                         "answer": "(P4-P1) x Q3.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 77,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-4 . Profit on a typical unit sold for a profit-maximizing monopoly would equal",
                         "options": [
                              "P5-P0.",
                              "P4-P2.",
                              "P4-P1.",
                              "P4-P3."
                         ],
                         "answer": "P4-P1.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 78,
                         "topic": "Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-4 . At the profit-maximizing level of output,",
                         "options": [
                              "marginal revenue is equal to P3.",
                              "marginal cost is equal to P3.",
                              "average revenue is equal to P4.",
                              "average total cost is equal to P0."
                         ],
                         "answer": "average revenue is equal to P4.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 79,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-5. What price will the monopolist charge?",
                         "options": [
                              "A",
                              "B",
                              "C",
                              "F"
                         ],
                         "answer": "B",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 80,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-5. How much output will the monopolist produce?",
                         "options": [
                              "O",
                              "J",
                              "K",
                              "L"
                         ],
                         "answer": "K",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 81,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-5. What area measures the monopolist’s profit?",
                         "options": [
                              "(B-F)*K",
                              "(A-H)*J",
                              "(B-G)*K",
                              "\"0.5[(B-F)*(L-K)]\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "(B-G)*K",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 82,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-6. In order to maximize profits, the monopolist should produce",
                         "options": [
                              "9 units.",
                              "12 units.",
                              "15 units.",
                              "more than 15 units."
                         ],
                         "answer": "12 units.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 83,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-6. In order to maximize profits, the monopolist should charge a price of",
                         "options": [
                              "$9.",
                              "$12.",
                              "$20.",
                              "$23."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$20.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 84,
                         "topic": "Total revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-6. A profit-maximizing monopolist would earn total revenues of",
                         "options": [
                              "$81.",
                              "$144.",
                              "$225.",
                              "$240."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$240.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 85,
                         "topic": "Total cost",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-6. A profit-maximizing monopolist would incur total costs of",
                         "options": [
                              "$81.",
                              "$120.",
                              "$144.",
                              "$240."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$120.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 86,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-6. A profit-maximizing monopolist would earn profits of",
                         "options": [
                              "$96.",
                              "$117.",
                              "$120.",
                              "$126."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$120.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 87,
                         "topic": "Total revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Table 15-1 . If the monopolist sells 8 units of its product, how much total revenue will it receive from the sale?",
                         "options": [
                              "$14",
                              "$40",
                              "$112",
                              "$164"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$112",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 88,
                         "topic": "Total revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Table 15-1 . If the monopolist wants to maximize its revenue, how many units of its product should it sell?",
                         "options": [
                              "4",
                              "5",
                              "6",
                              "8"
                         ],
                         "answer": "6",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 89,
                         "topic": "Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Table 15-1 . When 4 units of output are produced and sold, what is average revenue?",
                         "options": [
                              "$17",
                              "$21",
                              "$23",
                              "$26"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$26",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 90,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Table 15-1 . What is the marginal revenue for the monopolist for the sixth unit sold?",
                         "options": [
                              "$3",
                              "$5",
                              "$11",
                              "$17"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$5",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 91,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Table 15-1 . Assume this monopolist's marginal cost is constant at $12. What quantity of output (Q) will it produce and what price (P) will it charge?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"Q = 4, P = $29\"",
                              "\"Q = 4, P = $26\"",
                              "\"Q = 5, P = $23\"",
                              "\"Q = 7, P = $17\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"Q = 4, P = $26\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 92,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-2\nTanya has the following demand curve for selling taffy. Assume that Tanya has a marginal cost of $3 per unit.\nRefer to Table 15-2 . What is Tanya's profit-maximizing level of output?",
                         "options": [
                              "1",
                              "2",
                              "3",
                              "4"
                         ],
                         "answer": "2",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 93,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-2\nTanya has the following demand curve for selling taffy. Assume that Tanya has a marginal cost of $3 per unit.\nRefer to Table 15-2 . What is Tanya's profit-maximizing price?",
                         "options": [
                              "$2",
                              "$4",
                              "$6",
                              "$8"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$8",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 94,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-3\nConsider the following demand and cost information for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-3 . The marginal revenue of the 2nd unit is",
                         "options": [
                              "$10.",
                              "$15.",
                              "$20.",
                              "$25."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$15.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 95,
                         "topic": "Marginal cost",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-3\nConsider the following demand and cost information for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-3 . The marginal cost of the 4th unit is",
                         "options": [
                              "$7.",
                              "$12.",
                              "$25.",
                              "$60."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$7.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 96,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-3\nConsider the following demand and cost information for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-3 . The maximum profit this monopolist can earn is",
                         "options": [
                              "$5.",
                              "$15.",
                              "$16.",
                              "$28."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$28.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 97,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-3\nConsider the following demand and cost information for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-3 . To maximize profit, the monopolist sets price at",
                         "options": [
                              "$10.",
                              "$15.",
                              "$20.",
                              "$25."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$20.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 98,
                         "topic": "Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-4\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-4. If the monopolist produces 10 units, what is its average revenue?",
                         "options": [
                              "$100",
                              "$15",
                              "$10",
                              "$1"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$10",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 99,
                         "topic": "Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-4\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-4. If the monopolist produces 5 units, what is its average revenue?",
                         "options": [
                              "$100",
                              "$20",
                              "$5",
                              "$4"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$20",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 100,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-4\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-4. If the monopolist produces 10 units, what is its marginal revenue?",
                         "options": [
                              "$12.50",
                              "$5",
                              "-$5",
                              "-$12.50"
                         ],
                         "answer": "-$5",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 101,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-4\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-4. If the monopolist produces 5 units, what is its marginal revenue?",
                         "options": [
                              "$100",
                              "$37.5",
                              "$15",
                              "$2.50"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$15",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 102,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-4\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-4. The monopolist will not produce",
                         "options": [
                              "5 units or fewer under any circumstances.",
                              "7.5 units or fewer under any circumstances.",
                              "7.5 units or more under any circumstances.",
                              "10 units or more under any circumstances."
                         ],
                         "answer": "10 units or more under any circumstances.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 103,
                         "topic": "Total revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-4\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-4. In order to maximize total revenues, the monopolist should produce",
                         "options": [
                              "5 units.",
                              "7.5 units.",
                              "10 units.",
                              "12.5 units."
                         ],
                         "answer": "7.5 units.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 104,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-4\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-4. In order to maximize profits, the monopolist should produce",
                         "options": [
                              "7.5 units.",
                              "10 units.",
                              "where marginal revenue equals marginal cost.",
                              "Both a) and c) are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "where marginal revenue equals marginal cost.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 105,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-5\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-5. The monopolist has total fixed costs of $60 and has a constant marginal cost of $15. What is the profit-maximizing level of production?",
                         "options": [
                              "2 units",
                              "3 units",
                              "4 units",
                              "5 units"
                         ],
                         "answer": "4 units",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 106,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-5\nA monopolist faces the. following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-5. The monopolist has total fixed costs of $60 and has a constant marginal cost of $15. What is the profit-maximizing price?",
                         "options": [
                              "$4",
                              "$39",
                              "$36",
                              "$42"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$36",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 107,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-6\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-6. What is the marginal revenue from the sale of the 2nd unit?",
                         "options": [
                              "$-3",
                              "$3",
                              "$9",
                              "$24"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$9",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 108,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-6\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-6. What is the marginal revenue from the sale of the 3rd unit?",
                         "options": [
                              "$-3",
                              "$3",
                              "$9",
                              "$24"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$3",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 109,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-6\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-6. What is the marginal revenue from the sale of the 4th unit?",
                         "options": [
                              "$-3",
                              "$3",
                              "$9",
                              "$24"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$-3",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 110,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-6\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-6. If the monopolist has a constant marginal cost for her product equal to $7, what is her profit-maximizing price?",
                         "options": [
                              "$6",
                              "$9",
                              "$12",
                              "$15"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$12",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 111,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-6\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-6. Suppose the monopolist has total fixed costs equal to $5 and a variable cost equal to $4 per unit for all units produced. What is the profit-maximizing price?",
                         "options": [
                              "$6",
                              "$9",
                              "$12",
                              "$15"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$12",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 112,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-6\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-6. Suppose the monopolist has total fixed costs equal to $5 and a variable cost equal to $4 per unit for all units produced. What is the total profit if she operates at her profit-maximizing price?",
                         "options": [
                              "$1",
                              "$7",
                              "$9",
                              "$11"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$11",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 113,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-6\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-6. Suppose the monopolist has total fixed costs equal to $5 and a variable cost equal to $4 per unit for all units produced. What would the total profit be if she charged $6 per unit for her product?",
                         "options": [
                              "$1",
                              "$3",
                              "$8",
                              "$15"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$3",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 114,
                         "topic": "Marginal cost",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-7\nSally owns the only shoe store in town. She has the following cost and revenue information.\nRefer to Table 15-7 . What is the marginal cost of the 6th pair of shoes?",
                         "options": [
                              "$44",
                              "$46",
                              "$55",
                              "$60"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$60",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 115,
                         "topic": "Marginal cost",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-7\nSally owns the only shoe store in town. She has the following cost and revenue information.\nRefer to Table 15-7 . What is the marginal cost of the 8th pair of shoes?",
                         "options": [
                              "$50",
                              "$60",
                              "$90",
                              "$110"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$90",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 116,
                         "topic": "Total revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-7\nSally owns the only shoe store in town. She has the following cost and revenue information.\nRefer to Table 15-7 . What is the total revenue from selling 6 pairs of shoes?",
                         "options": [
                              "$100",
                              "$600",
                              "$625",
                              "$660"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$660",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 117,
                         "topic": "Total revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-7\nSally owns the only shoe store in town. She has the following cost and revenue information.\nRefer to Table 15-7 . What is the total revenue from selling 8 pairs of shoes?",
                         "options": [
                              "$90",
                              "$695",
                              "$720",
                              "$800"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$720",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 118,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-7\nSally owns the only shoe store in town. She has the following cost and revenue information.\nRefer to Table 15-7 . What is the marginal revenue from selling the 2nd pair of shoes?",
                         "options": [
                              "$140",
                              "$150",
                              "$160",
                              "$170"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$140",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 119,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-7\nSally owns the only shoe store in town. She has the following cost and revenue information.\nRefer to Table 15-7 . What is the marginal revenue from selling the 8th pair of shoes?",
                         "options": [
                              "$10",
                              "$20",
                              "$40",
                              "$90"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$20",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 120,
                         "topic": "Average revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-7\nSally owns the only shoe store in town. She has the following cost and revenue information.\nRefer to Table 15-7 . What is the average revenue when Sally sells 7 pairs of shoes?",
                         "options": [
                              "$40",
                              "$90",
                              "$100",
                              "$700"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$100",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 121,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Table 15-7 . Sally will maximize her profits by selling",
                         "options": [
                              "3 pairs of shoes.",
                              "4 pairs of shoes.",
                              "6 pairs of shoes.",
                              "7 pairs of shoes."
                         ],
                         "answer": "6 pairs of shoes.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 122,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Table 15-7 . What is total profit at the profit-maximizing quantity?",
                         "options": [
                              "$100",
                              "$245",
                              "$265",
                              "$395"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$265",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 123,
                         "topic": "Fixed costs",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Table 15-7 . What are Sally's fixed costs?",
                         "options": [
                              "$0",
                              "$100",
                              "$600",
                              "$745"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$100",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 124,
                         "topic": "Variable costs",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Table 15-7 . What is the total variable cost of production when Sally produces six pairs of shoes?",
                         "options": [
                              "$100",
                              "$295",
                              "$600",
                              "$620"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$295",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 125,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-8\nThe following table provides information on the price, quantity, and average total cost for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-8. How much extra revenue does the monopolist earn when he lowers the price from $18 to $12?",
                         "options": [
                              "$10",
                              "$12",
                              "$30",
                              "$41"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$30",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 126,
                         "topic": "Marginal cost",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-8\nThe following table provides information on the price, quantity, and average total cost for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-8. What is the additional cost to the firm when the monopolist lowers the price from $18 to $12?",
                         "options": [
                              "The firm saves $15.",
                              "$15",
                              "$30",
                              "$40"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$40",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 127,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-8\nThe following table provides information on the price, quantity, and average total cost for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-8. At what price will the monopolist maximize his profit?",
                         "options": [
                              "$6",
                              "$12",
                              "$18",
                              "$24"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$18",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 128,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-8\nThe following table provides information on the price, quantity, and average total cost for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-8. What is the maximum profit that the monopolist can earn?",
                         "options": [
                              "$10",
                              "$20",
                              "$30",
                              "$40"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$20",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 129,
                         "topic": "Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-9\nConsider the following demand and cost information for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-9. What is the marginal revenue of the 3rd unit?",
                         "options": [
                              "$4",
                              "$12",
                              "$20",
                              "$28"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$12",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 130,
                         "topic": "Marginal cost",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-9\nConsider the following demand and cost information for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-9. What is the marginal cost of the 4th unit?",
                         "options": [
                              "$4",
                              "$14",
                              "$31",
                              "$62"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$14",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 131,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-9\nConsider the following demand and cost information for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-9. What price should the monopoly charge to maximize profit?",
                         "options": [
                              "$16",
                              "$20",
                              "$24",
                              "$28"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$24",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 132,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-9\nConsider the following demand and cost information for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-9. At the profit-maximizing price, how much profit will the monopoly earn?",
                         "options": [
                              "$8",
                              "$10",
                              "$12",
                              "$14"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$14",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 133,
                         "topic": "Average total cost",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-9\nConsider the following demand and cost information for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-9. What is the monopolist’s average total cost of production at the profit-maximizing price?",
                         "options": [
                              "$12",
                              "$14",
                              "$16",
                              "$17"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$17",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 134,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-10\nThe monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-10. If the monopolist has total fixed costs of $40 and a constant marginal cost of $5, what is the profit-maximizing level of output?",
                         "options": [
                              "7 units",
                              "16 units",
                              "23 units",
                              "31 units"
                         ],
                         "answer": "16 units",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 135,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-10\nThe monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-10. If the monopolist has total fixed costs of $40 and a constant marginal cost of $5, how much profit can the firm earn at the profit-maximizing level of output?",
                         "options": [
                              "$128",
                              "$120",
                              "$80",
                              "$8"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$8",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 136,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-11\nThe following table shows quantity, price, and marginal cost information for a monopoly:\nRefer to Table 15-11. What price should the firm charge to maximize its profit?",
                         "options": [
                              "$4",
                              "$5",
                              "$6",
                              "$7"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$7",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 137,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-11\nThe following table shows quantity, price, and marginal cost information for a monopoly:\nRefer to Table 15-11. What level of output should the firm produce to maximize its profit?",
                         "options": [
                              "2 units",
                              "3 units",
                              "4 units",
                              "5 units"
                         ],
                         "answer": "3 units",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 138,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization | Marginal revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-11\nThe following table shows quantity, price, and marginal cost information for a monopoly:\nRefer to Table 15-11. What would be the firm’s marginal revenue at the profit-maximizing level of output?",
                         "options": [
                              "$7",
                              "$6",
                              "$5",
                              "$1"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$5",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 139,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-12\nThe following table provides information on the price, quantity, and average total cost for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-12. At what price will the firm maximize its profit?",
                         "options": [
                              "$1",
                              "$2",
                              "$3",
                              "$4"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$3",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 140,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-12\nThe following table provides information on the price, quantity, and average total cost for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-12. In order to maximize profits, the firm should produce",
                         "options": [
                              "4 units of output.",
                              "8 units of output.",
                              "12 units of output.",
                              "16 units of output."
                         ],
                         "answer": "8 units of output.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 141,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-12\nThe following table provides information on the price, quantity, and average total cost for a monopoly.\nRefer to Table 15-12. If the firm produces the profit-maximizing level of output, it will earn profits of",
                         "options": [
                              "$24.",
                              "$18.",
                              "$15.",
                              "$12."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$18.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 142,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-13\nThe following table gives information on the price, quantity, and total cost of production for a monopolist.\nRefer to Table 15-13. If the monopolist maximizes profits, he will charge a price of",
                         "options": [
                              "$4.",
                              "$3.",
                              "$2.",
                              "$1."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$4.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 143,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-13\nThe following table gives information on the price, quantity, and total cost of production for a monopolist.\nRefer to Table 15-13. How much profit will the firm earn at the profit-maximizing price?",
                         "options": [
                              "$9",
                              "$12",
                              "$15",
                              "$18"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$12",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 144,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-14\nThe following table gives information on the price, quantity, and total cost of production for a monopolist.\nRefer to Table 15-14. At what price does marginal revenue equal marginal cost?",
                         "options": [
                              "$5",
                              "$4",
                              "$3",
                              "$2"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$3",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 145,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-15\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-15. The monopolist has total fixed costs of $40 and a constant marginal cost of $5. At the profit-maximizing level of output, the monopolist's profit is",
                         "options": [
                              "$88.",
                              "$8.",
                              "$6.",
                              "We do not have enough information to determine profit."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$8.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 146,
                         "topic": "Average total cost",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Table 15-16\nA monopolist faces the following demand curve:\nRefer to Table 15-16. The monopolist has total fixed costs of $40 and a constant marginal cost of $5. At the profit-maximizing level of output, the monopolist's average total cost is",
                         "options": [
                              "$9.00.",
                              "$7.50.",
                              "$6.74.",
                              "$5.82."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$7.50.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 147,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Table 15-17. If a monopolist faces a constant marginal cost of $5, how much output should the firm produce?",
                         "options": [
                              "3 units",
                              "4 units",
                              "5 units",
                              "6 units"
                         ],
                         "answer": "3 units",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 148,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Table 15-17. If a monopolist faces a constant marginal cost of $4, how much output should the firm produce?",
                         "options": [
                              "3 units",
                              "4 units",
                              "5 units",
                              "6 units"
                         ],
                         "answer": "3 units",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 149,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Table 15-17. If a monopolist faces a constant marginal cost of $3, how much output should the firm produce in order to equate marginal revenue with marginal cost?",
                         "options": [
                              "3 units",
                              "4 units",
                              "5 units",
                              "6 units"
                         ],
                         "answer": "4 units",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 150,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Table 15-17. If a monopolist faces a constant marginal cost of $2, how much output should the firm produce?",
                         "options": [
                              "3 units",
                              "4 units",
                              "5 units",
                              "6 units"
                         ],
                         "answer": "4 units",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 151,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Table 15-17. If a monopolist faces a constant marginal cost of $1, how much output should the firm produce in order to equate marginal revenue with marginal cost?",
                         "options": [
                              "3 units",
                              "4 units",
                              "5 units",
                              "6 units"
                         ],
                         "answer": "5 units",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 152,
                         "topic": "Pricing",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-3\nA monopoly firm maximizes its profit by producing Q = 500 units of output. At that level of output, its marginal revenue is $30, its average revenue is $60, and its average total cost is $34.\nRefer to Scenario 15-3 . The firm's profit-maximizing price is",
                         "options": [
                              "$30.",
                              "between $30 and $34.",
                              "between $34 and $60.",
                              "$60."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$60.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 153,
                         "topic": "Total revenue",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-3\nA monopoly firm maximizes its profit by producing Q = 500 units of output. At that level of output, its marginal revenue is $30, its average revenue is $60, and its average total cost is $34.\nRefer to Scenario 15-3 . At Q = 500, the firm's total revenue is",
                         "options": [
                              "\"$13,000.\"",
                              "\"$15,000.\"",
                              "\"$17,000.\"",
                              "\"$30,000.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$30,000.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 154,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-3\nA monopoly firm maximizes its profit by producing Q = 500 units of output. At that level of output, its marginal revenue is $30, its average revenue is $60, and its average total cost is $34.\nRefer to Scenario 15-3. At Q = 500, the firm's profit is",
                         "options": [
                              "\"$13,000.\"",
                              "\"$15,000.\"",
                              "\"$17,000.\"",
                              "\"$30,000.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$13,000.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 155,
                         "topic": "Marginal cost",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-3\nA monopoly firm maximizes its profit by producing Q = 500 units of output. At that level of output, its marginal revenue is $30, its average revenue is $60, and its average total cost is $34.\nRefer to Scenario 15-3 . At Q = 500, the firm's marginal cost is",
                         "options": [
                              "less than $30.",
                              "$30.",
                              "$34.",
                              "greater than $34."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$30.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 156,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopolist maximizes profits by",
                         "options": [
                              "producing an output level where marginal revenue equals marginal cost.",
                              "charging a price equal to marginal revenue and marginal cost.",
                              "charging a price where marginal cost equals average total cost.",
                              "Both a and b are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "producing an output level where marginal revenue equals marginal cost.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 157,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopolist maximizes profits by",
                         "options": [
                              "producing an output level where marginal revenue equals marginal cost.",
                              "charging a price that is greater than marginal revenue.",
                              "earning a profit of (P - MC) x Q.",
                              "Both a and b are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Both a and b are correct.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 158,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A profit-maximizing monopolist will produce the level of output at which",
                         "options": [
                              "average revenue is equal to average total cost.",
                              "average revenue is equal to marginal cost.",
                              "marginal revenue is equal to marginal cost.",
                              "total revenue is equal to opportunity cost."
                         ],
                         "answer": "marginal revenue is equal to marginal cost.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 159,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a profit-maximizing monopolist,",
                         "options": [
                              "P > MR = MC.",
                              "P = MR = MC.",
                              "P > MR > MC.",
                              "MR < MC < P."
                         ],
                         "answer": "P > MR = MC.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 160,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The monopolist's profit-maximizing quantity of output is determined by the intersection of which of the following two curves?",
                         "options": [
                              "marginal cost and demand",
                              "marginal cost and marginal revenue",
                              "average total cost and marginal revenue",
                              "average variable cost and average revenue"
                         ],
                         "answer": "marginal cost and marginal revenue",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 161,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopolist will choose to increase output when",
                         "options": [
                              "market price increases.",
                              "\"at all levels of output, marginal cost increases.\"",
                              "\"at the present level of output, marginal revenue exceeds marginal cost.\"",
                              "the demand curve shifts to the left."
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"at the present level of output, marginal revenue exceeds marginal cost.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 162,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "The competitive firm produces where P = MC.",
                              "The monopolist produces where P = MC.",
                              "The competitive firm produces where MR = MC.",
                              "The monopolist produces where MR = MC."
                         ],
                         "answer": "The monopolist produces where P = MC.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 163,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"If the monopolist's marginal revenue is greater than its marginal cost, the monopolist can increase profit by selling more units at a lower price per unit.\"",
                              "\"If the monopolist's marginal revenue is greater than its marginal cost, the monopolist can increase profit by selling fewer units at a higher price per unit.\"",
                              "\"When a monopolist produces where price equals the minimum of average total cost, it earns a positive economic profit.\"",
                              "\"If the monopolist is earning a positive economic profit, it must be producing where MR = MC.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"If the monopolist's marginal revenue is greater than its marginal cost, the monopolist can increase profit by selling more units at a lower price per unit.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 164,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A reduction in a monopolist's fixed costs would",
                         "options": [
                              "decrease the profit-maximizing price and increase the profit-maximizing quantity produced.",
                              "increase the profit-maximizing price and decrease the profit-maximizing quantity produced.",
                              "not effect the profit-maximizing price or quantity.",
                              "\"possibly increase, decrease or not effect profit-maximizing price and quantity, depending on the elasticity of demand.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "not effect the profit-maximizing price or quantity.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 165,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Suppose when a monopolist produces 50 units its average revenue is $8 per unit, its marginal revenue is $4 per unit, its marginal cost is $4 per unit, and its average total cost is $3 per unit. What can we conclude about this monopolist?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"The monopolist is currently maximizing profits, and its total profits are $200.\"",
                              "\"The monopolist is currently maximizing profits, and its total profits are $250.\"",
                              "The monopolist is not currently maximizing its profits; it should produce more units and charge a lower price to maximize profit.",
                              "The monopolist is not currently maximizing its profits; it should produce fewer units and charger a higher price to maximize profit."
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"The monopolist is currently maximizing profits, and its total profits are $250.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 166,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Suppose when a monopolist produces 75 units its average revenue is $10 per unit, its marginal revenue is $5 per unit, its marginal cost is $6 per unit, and its average total cost is $5 per unit. What can we conclude about this monopolist?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"The monopolist is currently maximizing profits, and its total profits are $375.\"",
                              "\"The monopolist is currently maximizing profits, and its total profits are $300.\"",
                              "The monopolist is not currently maximizing profits; it should produce more units and charge a lower price to maximize profits.",
                              "The monopolist is not currently maximizing profits; it should produce fewer units and charge a higher price to maximize profits."
                         ],
                         "answer": "The monopolist is not currently maximizing profits; it should produce fewer units and charge a higher price to maximize profits.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 167,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A profit-maximizing monopolist charges a price of $12. The intersection of the marginal revenue and marginal cost curves occurs where output is 10 units and marginal cost is $6. Average total cost for 10 units of output is $5. What is the monopolist’s profit?",
                         "options": [
                              "$60",
                              "$70",
                              "$100",
                              "$120"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$70",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 168,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A profit-maximizing monopolist charges a price of $14. The intersection of the marginal revenue curve and the marginal cost curve occurs where output is 15 units and marginal cost is $7. What is the monopolist’s profit?",
                         "options": [
                              "$90",
                              "$105",
                              "$180",
                              "Not enough information is given to determine the answer."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Not enough information is given to determine the answer.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 169,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If a monopolist sells 100 units at $8 per unit and realizes an average total cost of $6 per unit, what is the monopolist's profit?",
                         "options": [
                              "$200",
                              "$400",
                              "$600",
                              "$800"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$200",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 170,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Suppose a monopolist charges a price of $27 for its product and sells 10 units at that price. At 10 units of production the firm has average fixed cost equal to $10 and average variable cost equal to $12. How much total profit is the firm earning at this price?",
                         "options": [
                              "$5",
                              "$25",
                              "$50",
                              "$140"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$50",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 171,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following formulas would correctly calculate a monopolist’s profit?",
                         "options": [
                              "profit = price – marginal cost",
                              "profit = price – average total cost",
                              "profit = (price – marginal cost)  quantity",
                              "profit = (price – average total cost)  quantity"
                         ],
                         "answer": "profit = (price – average total cost)  quantity",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 172,
                         "topic": "Marginal cost",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopoly's marginal cost will",
                         "options": [
                              "be less than its average fixed cost.",
                              "be less than the price per unit of its product.",
                              "exceed its marginal revenue.",
                              "equal its average total cost."
                         ],
                         "answer": "be less than the price per unit of its product.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 173,
                         "topic": "Patents",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If a pharmaceutical company discovers a new drug and successfully patents it, patent law gives the firm",
                         "options": [
                              "partial ownership of the right to sell the drug for a limited number of years.",
                              "partial ownership of the right to sell the drug for an unlimited number of years.",
                              "sole ownership of the right to sell the drug for a limited number of years.",
                              "sole ownership of the right to sell the drug for an unlimited number of years."
                         ],
                         "answer": "sole ownership of the right to sell the drug for a limited number of years.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 174,
                         "topic": "Patents",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Due to the nature of the patent laws on pharmaceuticals, the market for such drugs",
                         "options": [
                              "always remains a competitive market.",
                              "always remains a monopolistic market.",
                              "switches from competitive to monopolistic once the firm's patent runs out.",
                              "switches from monopolistic to competitive once the firm's patent runs out."
                         ],
                         "answer": "switches from monopolistic to competitive once the firm's patent runs out.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 175,
                         "topic": "Patents",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "What happens to the price and quantity sold of a drug when its patent runs out?\n(i) The price will fall.\n(ii) The quantity sold will fall.\n(iii) The marginal cost of producing the drug will rise.",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) only",
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(ii) and (iii) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "(i) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 176,
                         "topic": "Patents",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Generic drugs enter the pharmaceutical drug market once",
                         "options": [
                              "the ingredients to the name brand drug have been discovered.",
                              "10 years have passed.",
                              "they are patented.",
                              "the patent on the name brand drug expires."
                         ],
                         "answer": "the patent on the name brand drug expires.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 177,
                         "topic": "Patents",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Name brand drugs are able to continue capitalizing on their market power even after generic drugs enter the market because\n(i) almost all people fear the generic drug companies are devoting too few resources to research and development.\n(ii) some people fear that generic drugs are inferior.\n(iii) some people are loyal to the name brand.",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(ii) and (iii) only",
                              "(i) and (iii) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "(ii) and (iii) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 178,
                         "topic": "Patents",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "After the patent runs out on a brand name drug, generic drugs enter the market. What happens next in the market?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"Price increases, and total surplus decreases.\"",
                              "\"Price decreases, and total surplus decreases.\"",
                              "\"Price decreases, and total surplus increases.\"",
                              "\"Price increases, and total surplus increases.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"Price decreases, and total surplus increases.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 179,
                         "topic": "Supply curve",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopolist",
                         "options": [
                              "\"has a supply curve that is upward-sloping, just like a competitive firm.\"",
                              "does not have a supply curve because the monopolist sets its price at the same time it chooses the quantity to supply.",
                              "\"has a horizontal supply curve, just like a competitive firm.\"",
                              "does not have a supply curve because marginal revenue exceeds the price it charges for its products."
                         ],
                         "answer": "does not have a supply curve because the monopolist sets its price at the same time it chooses the quantity to supply.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 180,
                         "topic": "Supply curve",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The supply curve for the monopolist",
                         "options": [
                              "is horizontal.",
                              "is vertical.",
                              "is upward sloping.",
                              "does not exist."
                         ],
                         "answer": "does not exist.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 181,
                         "topic": "Supply curve",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "In a competitive market, a firm's supply curve dictates the amount it will supply. In a monopoly market the",
                         "options": [
                              "same is true.",
                              "\"supply curve conceptually makes sense, but in practice is never used.\"",
                              "supply curve will have limited predictive capacity.",
                              "decision about how much to supply is impossible to separate from the demand curve it faces."
                         ],
                         "answer": "decision about how much to supply is impossible to separate from the demand curve it faces.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    }
               ]
          },
          "sector4": {
               "title": "THE WELFARE COST OF MONOPOLY",
               "questions": [
                    {
                         "q_num": 1,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Monopolies are inefficient because they\n(i) eliminate barriers to entry.\n(ii) price their product at a level where marginal revenue exceeds marginal cost.\n(iii) restrict output below the socially efficient level of production.",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(ii) and (iii) only",
                              "(iii) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "(iii) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 2,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopolist produces",
                         "options": [
                              "more than the socially efficient quantity of output but at a higher price than in a competitive market.",
                              "less than the socially efficient quantity of output but at a higher price than in a competitive market.",
                              "the socially efficient quantity of output but at a higher price than in a competitive market.",
                              "\"possibly more or possibly less than the socially efficient quantity of output, but definitely at a higher price than in a competitive market.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "less than the socially efficient quantity of output but at a higher price than in a competitive market.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 3,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "\"Monopolists do not worry about efficient production and minimizing costs since they can just pass along any increase in costs to their consumers.\" This statement is",
                         "options": [
                              "\"false; price increases will mean fewer sales, which may lower profits.\"",
                              "true; this is the primary reason why economists believe that monopolies result in economic inefficiency.",
                              "false; the monopolist is a price taker.",
                              "true; consumers in a monopoly market have no substitutes to turn to when the monopolist raises prices."
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"false; price increases will mean fewer sales, which may lower profits.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 4,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Deadweight loss",
                         "options": [
                              "measures monopoly inefficiency.",
                              "exceeds monopoly profits.",
                              "equals monopoly profits.",
                              "equals monopoly revenues minus profits."
                         ],
                         "answer": "measures monopoly inefficiency.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 5,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopoly is an inefficient way to produce a product because",
                         "options": [
                              "it can earn both short-run and long-run profits.",
                              "it faces a downward-sloping demand curve.",
                              "the cost to the monopolist of producing one more unit exceeds the value of that unit to potential buyers.",
                              "it produces a smaller level of output than would be produced in a competitive market."
                         ],
                         "answer": "it produces a smaller level of output than would be produced in a competitive market.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 6,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The deadweight loss associated with a monopoly occurs because the monopolist",
                         "options": [
                              "maximizes profits.",
                              "produces an output level less than the socially optimal level.",
                              "produces an output level greater than the socially optimal level.",
                              "equates marginal revenue with marginal cost."
                         ],
                         "answer": "produces an output level less than the socially optimal level.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 7,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The economic inefficiency of a monopolist can be measured by the",
                         "options": [
                              "number of consumers who are unable to purchase the product because of its high price.",
                              "excess profit generated by monopoly firms.",
                              "poor quality of service offered by monopoly firms.",
                              "deadweight loss."
                         ],
                         "answer": "deadweight loss.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 8,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The economic inefficiency of a monopolist can be measured by the",
                         "options": [
                              "deadweight loss.",
                              "value of the unrealized trades that could be made if the monopolist produced the socially-efficient output.",
                              "area above marginal cost but beneath demand from the monopoly output to the socially-efficient output.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 9,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Monopoly pricing prevents some mutually beneficial trades from taking place. These unrealized, mutually beneficial trades are",
                         "options": [
                              "of little concern to society.",
                              "a deadweight loss to society.",
                              "a sunk cost to society.",
                              "also observed in competitive markets."
                         ],
                         "answer": "a deadweight loss to society.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 10,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Monopoly pricing prevents some mutually beneficial trades from taking place. These unrealized, mutually beneficial trades are",
                         "options": [
                              "not a concern if a market is perfectly competitive.",
                              "a deadweight loss to society.",
                              "a function of the reduction in the quantity produced by a monopolist in comparison to a competitive market.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 11,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Monopoly pricing prevents some mutually beneficial trades from taking place. These unrealized, mutually beneficial trades are",
                         "options": [
                              "less of a concern for a monopoly than competitive market.",
                              "offset by the higher profits earned by a monopolist.",
                              "a function of the reduction in the quantity produced by a monopolist in comparison to a competitive market.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "a function of the reduction in the quantity produced by a monopolist in comparison to a competitive market.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 12,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The deadweight loss that arises from a monopoly is a consequence of the fact that the monopoly",
                         "options": [
                              "quantity is lower than the socially-optimal quantity.",
                              "price equals marginal revenue.",
                              "price is the same as average revenue.",
                              "earns positive profits."
                         ],
                         "answer": "quantity is lower than the socially-optimal quantity.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 13,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "The benefits that accrue to a monopoly’s owners are equal to the costs that are incurred by consumers of that firm's product.",
                              "The deadweight loss that arises in monopoly stems from the fact that the profit-maximizing monopoly firm produces a quantity of output that exceeds the socially-efficient quantity.",
                              "The deadweight loss caused by monopoly is similar to the deadweight loss caused by a tax on a product.",
                              "The primary social problem caused by monopoly is monopoly profit."
                         ],
                         "answer": "The deadweight loss caused by monopoly is similar to the deadweight loss caused by a tax on a product.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 14,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The social cost of a monopoly is equal to its",
                         "options": [
                              "economic profit.",
                              "fixed cost.",
                              "dead weight loss.",
                              "variable cost."
                         ],
                         "answer": "dead weight loss.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 15,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "Part of the deadweight loss associated with monopoly is measured by the monopolist's economic profit.",
                              "Marginal cost is always less than average total cost in a natural monopoly.",
                              "Discount coupons available free to the public are a type of price discrimination.",
                              "Anti-trust laws make it harder for firms to create synergies."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Part of the deadweight loss associated with monopoly is measured by the monopolist's economic profit.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 16,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Monopolies are socially inefficient because the price they charge is",
                         "options": [
                              "equal to marginal revenue.",
                              "above marginal cost.",
                              "equal to demand.",
                              "above demand."
                         ],
                         "answer": "above marginal cost.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 17,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is correct? Monopolies are socially inefficient because they\n(i) charge a price above marginal cost.\n(ii) produce too little output.\n(iii) earn profits at the expense of consumers.\n(iv) maximize the market’s total surplus.",
                         "options": [
                              "(iii) only",
                              "(iii) and (iv) only",
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), (iii), and (iv)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "(i) and (ii) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 18,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Consider a profit-maximizing monopoly pricing under the following conditions. The profit-maximizing quantity is 40 units, the profit-maximizing price is $160, and the marginal cost of the 40th unit is $120. If the good were produced in a perfectly competitive market, the equilibrium quantity would be 50, and the equilibrium price would be $150. The demand curve and marginal cost curves are linear. What is the value of the deadweight loss created by the monopolist?",
                         "options": [
                              "$40",
                              "$100",
                              "$200",
                              "$400"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$200",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 19,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Consider a profit-maximizing monopoly pricing under the following conditions. The profit-maximizing price charged for goods produced is $12.The intersection of the marginal revenue and marginal cost curves occurs where output is 10 units and marginal cost is $6. The socially efficient level of production is 12 units. The demand curve and marginal cost curves are linear. What is the value of the deadweight loss created by the monopolist?",
                         "options": [
                              "$4",
                              "$6",
                              "$12",
                              "$16"
                         ],
                         "answer": "$6",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 20,
                         "topic": "Welfare",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "When we compare economic welfare in a monopoly market to a competitive market, the profits earned by the monopolist represent",
                         "options": [
                              "a transfer of benefits from the consumer to the producer.",
                              "a loss in total welfare.",
                              "the higher marginal costs incurred by the monopolists in comparison to competitive firms.",
                              "the higher marginal revenues gained by the monopolists in comparison to competitive firms."
                         ],
                         "answer": "a transfer of benefits from the consumer to the producer.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 21,
                         "topic": "Welfare",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "When we compare economic welfare in a monopoly market to a competitive market, the profits earned by the monopolist represent",
                         "options": [
                              "a loss in total welfare.",
                              "a transfer of benefits from the buyer to the seller.",
                              "the higher marginal costs incurred by the monopolists in comparison to competitive firms.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "a transfer of benefits from the buyer to the seller.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 22,
                         "topic": "Welfare",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopoly market",
                         "options": [
                              "always maximizes total economic well-being.",
                              "always minimizes consumer surplus.",
                              "generally fails to maximize total economic well-being.",
                              "generally fails to maximize producer surplus."
                         ],
                         "answer": "generally fails to maximize total economic well-being.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 23,
                         "topic": "Welfare",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Suppose a monopolist chooses the price and production level that maximizes its profit. From that point, to increase society’s economic welfare, output would need to be increased as long as",
                         "options": [
                              "average revenue exceeds marginal cost.",
                              "average revenue exceeds average total cost.",
                              "marginal revenue exceeds marginal cost.",
                              "marginal revenue exceeds average total cost."
                         ],
                         "answer": "average revenue exceeds marginal cost.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 24,
                         "topic": "Welfare",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The socially efficient level of production occurs where the marginal cost curve intersects",
                         "options": [
                              "average variable cost.",
                              "average total cost.",
                              "demand.",
                              "marginal revenue."
                         ],
                         "answer": "demand.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 25,
                         "topic": "Welfare",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Many economists criticize monopolists because they",
                         "options": [
                              "charge a price that equals marginal cost rather than a price that equals average cost.",
                              "do not innovate.",
                              "produce a large quantity of waste.",
                              "produce less than the socially efficient level of output."
                         ],
                         "answer": "produce less than the socially efficient level of output.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 26,
                         "topic": "Welfare",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Selling a good at a price determined by the intersection of the demand curve and the marginal cost curve is consistent with the\n(i) socially-optimal level of output.\n(ii) market solution for profit-maximizing competitive firms.\n(iii) market solution for a profit-maximizing monopoly.",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(ii) and (iii) only",
                              "(i) and (iii) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "(i) and (ii) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 27,
                         "topic": "Welfare",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "When the government creates a monopoly, the social loss may include",
                         "options": [
                              "declining marginal costs.",
                              "the cost of lawyers and lobbyists hired to convince lawmakers to continue the monopoly.",
                              "excessive monopoly profits.",
                              "diminishing marginal revenue."
                         ],
                         "answer": "the cost of lawyers and lobbyists hired to convince lawmakers to continue the monopoly.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 28,
                         "topic": "Welfare",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If a social planner were running a monopoly, that planner could achieve an efficient outcome by charging the price that is determined by the",
                         "options": [
                              "minimum point on the average total cost curve.",
                              "intersection of the average total cost curve and the demand curve.",
                              "intersection of the marginal cost curve and the demand curve.",
                              "intersection of the marginal cost curve and the marginal revenue curve."
                         ],
                         "answer": "intersection of the marginal cost curve and the demand curve.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 29,
                         "topic": "Welfare",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a monopoly, the socially efficient level of output occurs where",
                         "options": [
                              "marginal revenue equals marginal cost.",
                              "average revenue equals marginal cost.",
                              "marginal revenue equals average total cost.",
                              "average revenue equals average total cost."
                         ],
                         "answer": "average revenue equals marginal cost.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 30,
                         "topic": "Total surplus",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The difference in total surplus between the socially efficient level of production and the monopolist's level of production is",
                         "options": [
                              "offset by regulatory revenues.",
                              "called a deadweight loss.",
                              "equal to the monopolist’s profit.",
                              "Both b and c are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "called a deadweight loss.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 31,
                         "topic": "Total surplus",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Economic welfare is generally measured by\n(i) profit.\n(ii) total surplus.\n(iii) the price consumers pay for the product.",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(ii) and (iii) only",
                              "(c) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "(c) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 32,
                         "topic": "Total surplus",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a monopoly market, total surplus can be defined as the value of the good to",
                         "options": [
                              "producers minus the cost incurred by consumers.",
                              "producers plus the cost incurred by consumers.",
                              "consumers minus the costs of producing the good.",
                              "consumers plus the cost of producing the good."
                         ],
                         "answer": "consumers minus the costs of producing the good.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 33,
                         "topic": "Total surplus",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "To maximize total surplus with a monopoly firm, a benevolent social planner would choose the level of output where",
                         "options": [
                              "MR = MC.",
                              "MR intersects the demand curve.",
                              "MC intersects the demand curve.",
                              "MR exceeds MC by the greatest amount."
                         ],
                         "answer": "MC intersects the demand curve.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 34,
                         "topic": "Consumer surplus",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Consumers' willingness to pay for a good minus the amount they actually pay for it equals",
                         "options": [
                              "consumer surplus.",
                              "consumer benefit.",
                              "price discriminant.",
                              "deadweight loss."
                         ],
                         "answer": "consumer surplus.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 35,
                         "topic": "Producer surplus",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The amount that producers receive for a good minus their costs of producing it equals",
                         "options": [
                              "quantity supplied.",
                              "supply price.",
                              "deadweight loss.",
                              "producer surplus."
                         ],
                         "answer": "producer surplus.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 36,
                         "topic": "Profit maximization",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopoly chooses to supply the market with a quantity of a product that is determined by the intersection of the",
                         "options": [
                              "marginal cost and demand curves.",
                              "average total cost and demand curves.",
                              "marginal revenue and average total cost curves.",
                              "marginal revenue and marginal cost curves."
                         ],
                         "answer": "marginal revenue and marginal cost curves.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 37,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-7. What is the socially efficient price and quantity?",
                         "options": [
                              "price = F; quantity = A",
                              "price = G; quantity = B",
                              "price = G; quantity = A",
                              "price = D; quantity = A"
                         ],
                         "answer": "price = G; quantity = B",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 38,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-7. What is the monopoly price and quantity?",
                         "options": [
                              "price = F; quantity = A",
                              "price = G; quantity = B",
                              "price = G; quantity = A",
                              "price = D; quantity = A"
                         ],
                         "answer": "price = F; quantity = A",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 39,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-7. What is the area of deadweight loss?",
                         "options": [
                              "the rectangle (F-D)xA",
                              "\"the triangle 1/2[(F-D)x(B-A)]\"",
                              "\"the triangle 1/2[(F-G)x(B-A)]\"",
                              "\"the rectangle (F-D)xA plus the triangle 1/2[(F-D)x(B-A)]\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"the triangle 1/2[(F-D)x(B-A)]\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 40,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-7. What area represents the total surplus lost due to monopoly pricing?",
                         "options": [
                              "the rectangle (F-D)xA",
                              "\"the triangle 1/2[(F-D)x(B-A)]\"",
                              "\"the triangle 1/2[(F-G)x(B-A)]\"",
                              "\"the rectangle (F-D)xA plus the triangle 1/2[(F-D)x(B-A)]\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"the triangle 1/2[(F-D)x(B-A)]\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    }
               ]
          },
          "sector5": {
               "title": "PRICE DISCRIMINATION",
               "questions": [
                    {
                         "q_num": 1,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Price discrimination",
                         "options": [
                              "is illegal in the United States and Europe.",
                              "can occur in both perfectly competitive and monopoly markets.",
                              "is illogical because it does not maximize profits.",
                              "can maximize profits if the seller can prevent the resale of goods between customers."
                         ],
                         "answer": "can maximize profits if the seller can prevent the resale of goods between customers.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 2,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Price discrimination is the business practice of",
                         "options": [
                              "bundling related products to increase total sales.",
                              "selling the same good at different prices to different customers.",
                              "pricing above marginal cost.",
                              "hiring marketing experts to increase consumers’ brand loyalty."
                         ],
                         "answer": "selling the same good at different prices to different customers.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 3,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "When a monopolist is able to sell its product at different prices, it is engaging in",
                         "options": [
                              "distribution pricing.",
                              "quality-adjusted pricing.",
                              "arbitrage.",
                              "price discrimination."
                         ],
                         "answer": "price discrimination.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 4,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The practice of selling the same goods to different customers at different prices, but with the same marginal cost, is known as",
                         "options": [
                              "price segregation.",
                              "price discrimination.",
                              "arbitrage.",
                              "monopoly pricing."
                         ],
                         "answer": "price discrimination.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 5,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a firm to price discriminate,",
                         "options": [
                              "it must be a natural monopoly.",
                              "it must be regulated by the government.",
                              "it must have some market power.",
                              "consumers must tell the firm what they are willing to pay for the product."
                         ],
                         "answer": "it must have some market power.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 6,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A rational pricing strategy for a profit-maximizing monopolist is",
                         "options": [
                              "price discrimination.",
                              "price segregation.",
                              "synergy pricing.",
                              "average cost pricing."
                         ],
                         "answer": "price discrimination.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 7,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Price discrimination requires the firm to",
                         "options": [
                              "separate customers according to their willingnesses to pay.",
                              "differentiate between different units of its product.",
                              "engage in arbitrage.",
                              "use coupons."
                         ],
                         "answer": "separate customers according to their willingnesses to pay.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 8,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following can eliminate the inefficiency inherent in monopoly pricing?",
                         "options": [
                              "arbitrage",
                              "cost-plus pricing",
                              "price discrimination",
                              "regulations that force monopolies to reduce their levels of output"
                         ],
                         "answer": "price discrimination",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 9,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A firm cannot price discriminate if it",
                         "options": [
                              "has perfect information about consumer demand.",
                              "operates in a competitive market.",
                              "faces a downward-sloping demand curve.",
                              "is regulated by the government."
                         ],
                         "answer": "operates in a competitive market.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 10,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A firm cannot price discriminate if",
                         "options": [
                              "its has declining marginal revenue.",
                              "it operates in a competitive market.",
                              "buyers only reveal the price they are willing to pay for the product.",
                              "it has a constant marginal cost."
                         ],
                         "answer": "it operates in a competitive market.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 11,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Price discrimination adds to social welfare in the form of\n(i),increased total surplus.\n(ii),reduced costs of production.\n(iii),increased consumer surplus.",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) only",
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(i) and (iii) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "(i) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 12,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Compared to the monopoly outcome with a single price, imperfect price discrimination\n(i),sometimes raises total surplus.\n(ii),sometimes lowers total surplus.\n(iii),always leads to a lower quantity of output.",
                         "options": [
                              "(i) and (ii) only",
                              "(ii) and (iii) only",
                              "(i) and (iii) only",
                              "\"(i), (ii), and (iii)\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "(i) and (ii) only",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 13,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Price discrimination",
                         "options": [
                              "forces monopolies to charge a lower price as a result of government regulation.",
                              "is an attempt by a monopoly to prevent some customers from purchasing its product by charging a high price.",
                              "is an attempt by a monopoly to increases its profit by selling the same good to different customers at different prices.",
                              "increases the consumer surplus associated with a monopolistic market."
                         ],
                         "answer": "is an attempt by a monopoly to increases its profit by selling the same good to different customers at different prices.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 14,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "What do economists call the business practice of selling the same good at difference prices to different customers?",
                         "options": [
                              "price discrimination",
                              "collusion",
                              "compensating differential",
                              "Both a and b are correct"
                         ],
                         "answer": "price discrimination",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 15,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopolist's profits with price discrimination will be",
                         "options": [
                              "\"lower than if the firm charged a single, profit-maximizing price\"",
                              "\"the same as if the firm charged a single, profit-maximizing price.\"",
                              "higher than if the firm charged just one price because the firm will capture more consumer surplus.",
                              "higher than if the firm charged a single price because the costs of selling the good will be lower."
                         ],
                         "answer": "higher than if the firm charged just one price because the firm will capture more consumer surplus.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 16,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following is not an example of price discrimination?",
                         "options": [
                              "A movie theater charges a lower price for a child’s ticket than for an adult’s ticket.",
                              "A university rebates part of the cost of tuition in the form of financial aid for needy students.",
                              "A local pizza chain offers a “buy three get one free” deal.",
                              "An ice cream parlor charges a higher price for ice cream than for sherbet."
                         ],
                         "answer": "An ice cream parlor charges a higher price for ice cream than for sherbet.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 17,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A movie theater can increase its profits through price discrimination by charging a higher price to adults and a lower price to children if it",
                         "options": [
                              "can prevent children from buying the lower-priced tickets and selling them to adults.",
                              "has some degree of monopoly pricing power.",
                              "can easily distinguish between the two groups of customers.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 18,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A movie theater can increase its profits through price discrimination by charging a higher price to adults and a lower price to children if",
                         "options": [
                              "adults buy more popcorn than children.",
                              "the cost of showing a movie to children is less than the cost of showing a movie to adults.",
                              "it has some degree of monopoly-pricing power.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "it has some degree of monopoly-pricing power.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 19,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Financial aid to college students, quantity discounts, and senior citizen discounts are all examples of",
                         "options": [
                              "consumer surplus.",
                              "deadweight loss.",
                              "price discrimination.",
                              "nonprofit pricing strategies."
                         ],
                         "answer": "price discrimination.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 20,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "When deciding what price to charge consumers, the monopolist may choose to charge them different prices based on the customers'",
                         "options": [
                              "geographical location.",
                              "age.",
                              "income.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 21,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Many movie theaters allow discount tickets to be sold to senior citizens because",
                         "options": [
                              "senior-citizen laws mandate such discounts.",
                              "goodwill efforts earn community respect and win loyal patrons.",
                              "the theaters are profit maximizers.",
                              "senior citizens lobby city councils for lower prices."
                         ],
                         "answer": "the theaters are profit maximizers.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 22,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Round-trip airline tickets are usually cheaper if you stay over a Saturday night before you fly back. What is the reason for this price discrepancy?",
                         "options": [
                              "Airlines are practicing imperfect price discrimination to raise their profits.",
                              "Airlines charge a different rate based on the different nature of peoples' travel needs.",
                              "Airlines are attempting to charge people based on their willingness to pay.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 23,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "When a local grocery store offers discount coupons in the Sunday paper it is most likely trying to",
                         "options": [
                              "reduce prices for all customers.",
                              "encourage literacy.",
                              "encourage arbitrage.",
                              "price discriminate."
                         ],
                         "answer": "price discriminate.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 24,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Price discrimination explains why Ivy League universities often base tuition costs on students'",
                         "options": [
                              "age.",
                              "financial resources.",
                              "high school GPA.",
                              "gender."
                         ],
                         "answer": "financial resources.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 25,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Some prescription drugs sell for more in the United States than they do in other countries. Which of the following statements about this issue is most likely to be true?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"Drug companies are engaging in price discrimination, and this practice certainly reduces global social welfare.\"",
                              "Global social welfare could be improved if the price in the United States were reduced to the price charged in other countries.",
                              "Global social welfare could be improved if the price in the other countries were increased to the price charged in the United States.",
                              "\"Drug companies are engaging in price discrimination, but this might improve global social welfare if it gives more people access to the drugs.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"Drug companies are engaging in price discrimination, but this might improve global social welfare if it gives more people access to the drugs.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 26,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following is not an example of price discrimination by a firm?",
                         "options": [
                              "children's meals at a restaurant",
                              "a natural gas company charging customers a higher rate in the winter than in the summer",
                              "a senior citizens' discount",
                              "coupons in the Sunday newspaper"
                         ],
                         "answer": "a natural gas company charging customers a higher rate in the winter than in the summer",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 27,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Customers who purchase an audio CD from Sally’s Sounds are charged 20% more than customers who purchase the audio CD from the Sally's Sounds website. This is an example of",
                         "options": [
                              "perfect price discrimination.",
                              "price discrimination.",
                              "deadweight loss.",
                              "socially inefficient output."
                         ],
                         "answer": "price discrimination.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 28,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "During the holiday season, high-end retailers frequently place a high price on merchandise on weekends and discount the price during the week. They do this because they believe that two groups of customers exist: shoppers with little free time and bargain hunters. Bargain hunters have time to shop around and frequently shop during the week. What do economists call this price strategy used by high-end retailers?",
                         "options": [
                              "oligopoly",
                              "price discrimination",
                              "compensating differential",
                              "in-kind transfers"
                         ],
                         "answer": "price discrimination",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 29,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following is an example of price discrimination?",
                         "options": [
                              "Nabisco provides cents-off coupons for its products.",
                              "Amtrak offers a lower price for weekend travel compared to weekday rates on the same routes.",
                              "Hotel rates for AAA members are lower than for nonmembers.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 30,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements comparing monopoly with competition is correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "A monopolist produces a higher level of output and charges a lower price than a competitive firm would.",
                              "\"With perfect price discrimination, the total surplus under monopoly can be the same as under competition.\"",
                              "\"With or without price discrimination, the consumer surplus under monopoly is at least as large as it would be under competition.\"",
                              "The deadweight loss associated with monopoly is caused by the positive economic profits of the monopolist; competitive firms do not earn a positive economic profit so there is no deadweight loss under competition."
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"With perfect price discrimination, the total surplus under monopoly can be the same as under competition.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 31,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Suppose a monopolist is able to charge each customer a price equal to that customer’s willingness-to-pay for the product. Then the monopolist is engaging in",
                         "options": [
                              "marginal cost pricing.",
                              "arbitrage pricing.",
                              "voodoo economics.",
                              "perfect price discrimination."
                         ],
                         "answer": "perfect price discrimination.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 32,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Suppose that a professional photographer takes a prize-winning digital photo. She can sell a 5\"x7\" color print of the photo for $10. She can also sell the digital file for $20. There are 500 people willing to buy the color print and 2,000 people willing to buy the digital file. Assume the costs to the photographer are zero and that the people who purchase the digital file cannot resell the file itself or any prints made from it. What should she do in order to maximize her profits?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"earn $5,000 by selling only the color prints\"",
                              "\"earn $40,000 by selling only the digital files\"",
                              "\"earn $45,000 by selling both the color prints and the digital files at their respective prices\"",
                              "We do not have enough information with which to answer this question."
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"earn $45,000 by selling both the color prints and the digital files at their respective prices\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 33,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-5: An airline knows that there are two types of travelers: business travelers and vacationers. For a particular flight, there are 100 business travelers who will pay $600 for a ticket while there are 50 vacationers who will pay $300 for a ticket. There are 150 seats available on the plane. Suppose the cost to the airline of providing the flight is $20,000, which includes the cost of the pilots, flight attendants, fuel, etc. Refer to Scenario 15-5. How much profit will the airline earn if it sets the price of each ticket at $600?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"-$5,000\"",
                              "\"$15,000\"",
                              "\"$40,000\"",
                              "\"$60,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$40,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 34,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-5: An airline knows that there are two types of travelers: business travelers and vacationers. For a particular flight, there are 100 business travelers who will pay $600 for a ticket while there are 50 vacationers who will pay $300 for a ticket. There are 150 seats available on the plane. Suppose the cost to the airline of providing the flight is $20,000, which includes the cost of the pilots, flight attendants, fuel, etc. Refer to Scenario 15-5. How much profit will the airline earn if it sets the price of each ticket at $300?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"-$15,000\"",
                              "\"-$5,000\"",
                              "\"$25,000\"",
                              "\"$45,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$25,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 35,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-5: An airline knows that there are two types of travelers: business travelers and vacationers. For a particular flight, there are 100 business travelers who will pay $600 for a ticket while there are 50 vacationers who will pay $300 for a ticket. There are 150 seats available on the plane. Suppose the cost to the airline of providing the flight is $20,000, which includes the cost of the pilots, flight attendants, fuel, etc. Refer to Scenario 15-5. How much profit will the airline earn if it engages in price discrimination?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"-$5,000\"",
                              "\"$40,000\"",
                              "\"$55,000\"",
                              "\"$75,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$55,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 36,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-5: An airline knows that there are two types of travelers: business travelers and vacationers. For a particular flight, there are 100 business travelers who will pay $600 for a ticket while there are 50 vacationers who will pay $300 for a ticket. There are 150 seats available on the plane. Suppose the cost to the airline of providing the flight is $20,000, which includes the cost of the pilots, flight attendants, fuel, etc. Refer to Scenario 15-5. How much additional profit can the airline earn by charging each customer their willingness to pay relative to charging a flat price of $600 per ticket?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"$15,000\"",
                              "\"$25,000\"",
                              "\"$40,000\"",
                              "\"$70,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$15,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 37,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-5: An airline knows that there are two types of travelers: business travelers and vacationers. For a particular flight, there are 100 business travelers who will pay $600 for a ticket while there are 50 vacationers who will pay $300 for a ticket. There are 150 seats available on the plane. Suppose the cost to the airline of providing the flight is $20,000, which includes the cost of the pilots, flight attendants, fuel, etc. Refer to Scenario 15-5. How much additional profit can the airline earn by charging each customer their willingness to pay relative to charging a flat price of $300 per ticket?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"$10,000\"",
                              "\"$15,000\"",
                              "\"$30,000\"",
                              "\"$45,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$30,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 38,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-6: The concert promoters of a heavy-metal band, WeR2Loud, know that there are two types of concert-goers: die-hard fans and casual fans. For a particular WeR2Loud concert, there are 1,000 die-hard fans who will pay $150 for a ticket and 500 casual fans who will pay $50 for a ticket. There are 1,500 seats available at the concert venue. Suppose the cost of putting on the concert is $50,000, which includes the cost of the band, lighting, security, etc. Refer to Scenario 15-6. How much profit will the concert promoters earn if they set the price of each ticket at $150?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"$75,000\"",
                              "\"$100,000\"",
                              "\"$150,000\"",
                              "\"$175,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$100,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 39,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-6: The concert promoters of a heavy-metal band, WeR2Loud, know that there are two types of concert-goers: die-hard fans and casual fans. For a particular WeR2Loud concert, there are 1,000 die-hard fans who will pay $150 for a ticket and 500 casual fans who will pay $50 for a ticket. There are 1,500 seats available at the concert venue. Suppose the cost of putting on the concert is $50,000, which includes the cost of the band, lighting, security, etc. Refer to Scenario 15-6. How much profit will the concert promoters earn if they set the price of each ticket at $50?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"$25,000\"",
                              "\"$75,000\"",
                              "\"$100,000\"",
                              "\"$150,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$25,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 40,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-6: The concert promoters of a heavy-metal band, WeR2Loud, know that there are two types of concert-goers: die-hard fans and casual fans. For a particular WeR2Loud concert, there are 1,000 die-hard fans who will pay $150 for a ticket and 500 casual fans who will pay $50 for a ticket. There are 1,500 seats available at the concert venue. Suppose the cost of putting on the concert is $50,000, which includes the cost of the band, lighting, security, etc. Refer to Scenario 15-6. How much profit will the concert promoters earn if they engage in price discrimination?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"$100,000\"",
                              "\"$125,000\"",
                              "\"$150,000\"",
                              "\"$175,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$125,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 41,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-6: The concert promoters of a heavy-metal band, WeR2Loud, know that there are two types of concert-goers: die-hard fans and casual fans. For a particular WeR2Loud concert, there are 1,000 die-hard fans who will pay $150 for a ticket and 500 casual fans who will pay $50 for a ticket. There are 1,500 seats available at the concert venue. Suppose the cost of putting on the concert is $50,000, which includes the cost of the band, lighting, security, etc. Refer to Scenario 15-6. How much additional profit can the concert promoters earn by charging each customer their willingness to pay relative to charging a flat price of $150 per ticket?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"$25,000\"",
                              "\"$50,000\"",
                              "\"$75,000\"",
                              "\"$100,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$25,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 42,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-6: The concert promoters of a heavy-metal band, WeR2Loud, know that there are two types of concert-goers: die-hard fans and casual fans. For a particular WeR2Loud concert, there are 1,000 die-hard fans who will pay $150 for a ticket and 500 casual fans who will pay $50 for a ticket. There are 1,500 seats available at the concert venue. Suppose the cost of putting on the concert is $50,000, which includes the cost of the band, lighting, security, etc. Refer to Scenario 15-6. How much additional profit can the concert promoters earn by charging each customer their willingness to pay relative to charging a flat price of $50 per ticket?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"$25,000\"",
                              "\"$50,000\"",
                              "\"$75,000\"",
                              "\"$100,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$100,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 43,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-7: Black Box Cable TV is able to purchase an exclusive right to sell a premium movie channel (PMC) in its market area. Let's assume that Black Box Cable pays $150,000 a year for the exclusive marketing rights to PMC. Since Black Box has already installed cable to all of the homes in its market area, the marginal cost of delivering PMC to subscribers is zero. The manager of Black Box needs to know what price to charge for the PMC service to maximize her profit. Before setting price, she hires an economist to estimate demand for the PMC service. The economist discovers that there are two types of subscribers who value premium movie channels. First are the 4,000 die-hard TV viewers who will pay as much as $150 a year for the new PMC premium channel. Second, the PMC channel will appeal to 20,000 occasional TV viewers who will pay as much as $20 a year for a subscription to PMC. Refer to Scenario 15-7. If Black Box Cable TV is unable to price discriminate, what price will it choose to maximize its profit, and what is the amount of the profit?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"price = $20; profit = $400,000\"",
                              "\"price = $20; profit = $330,000\"",
                              "\"price = $150; profit = $450,000\"",
                              "\"price = $150; profit = $600,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"price = $150; profit = $450,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 44,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-7: Black Box Cable TV is able to purchase an exclusive right to sell a premium movie channel (PMC) in its market area. Let's assume that Black Box Cable pays $150,000 a year for the exclusive marketing rights to PMC. Since Black Box has already installed cable to all of the homes in its market area, the marginal cost of delivering PMC to subscribers is zero. The manager of Black Box needs to know what price to charge for the PMC service to maximize her profit. Before setting price, she hires an economist to estimate demand for the PMC service. The economist discovers that there are two types of subscribers who value premium movie channels. First are the 4,000 die-hard TV viewers who will pay as much as $150 a year for the new PMC premium channel. Second, the PMC channel will appeal to 20,000 occasional TV viewers who will pay as much as $20 a year for a subscription to PMC. Refer to Scenario 15-7. If Black Box Cable TV is able to price discriminate, what would be the maximum amount of profit it could generate?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"$500,000\"",
                              "\"$600,000\"",
                              "\"$850,000\"",
                              "\"$925,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$850,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 45,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-7: Black Box Cable TV is able to purchase an exclusive right to sell a premium movie channel (PMC) in its market area. Let's assume that Black Box Cable pays $150,000 a year for the exclusive marketing rights to PMC. Since Black Box has already installed cable to all of the homes in its market area, the marginal cost of delivering PMC to subscribers is zero. The manager of Black Box needs to know what price to charge for the PMC service to maximize her profit. Before setting price, she hires an economist to estimate demand for the PMC service. The economist discovers that there are two types of subscribers who value premium movie channels. First are the 4,000 die-hard TV viewers who will pay as much as $150 a year for the new PMC premium channel. Second, the PMC channel will appeal to 20,000 occasional TV viewers who will pay as much as $20 a year for a subscription to PMC. Refer to Scenario 15-7. What is the deadweight loss associated with the nondiscriminating pricing policy compared to the price discriminating policy?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"$375,000\"",
                              "\"$400,000\"",
                              "\"$475,000\"",
                              "It cannot be determined from the information provided."
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$400,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 46,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-8: Mega Media Cable TV is able to purchase an exclusive right to sell a premium sports channel in its market area. Let's assume that Mega Media pays $100,000 a year for the exclusive marketing rights to the sports channel. Since Mega Media has already installed cable to all of the homes in its market area, the marginal cost of delivering the sports channel to subscribers is zero. The manager of Mega Media needs to know what price to charge for the sports channel service to maximize her profit. Before setting price, she hires an economist to estimate demand for the sports channel. The economist discovers that there are two types of subscribers who value premium sporting channels. First are the 3,000 die-hard sports fans who will pay as much as $150 a year for the new channel. Second, the premium sports channel will appeal to 20,000 occasional sports viewers who will pay as much as $25 a year for a subscription to it. Refer to Scenario 15-8. How much profit will Mega Media Cable TV earn if it sets the price at $25?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"$350,000\"",
                              "\"$450,000\"",
                              "\"$475,000\"",
                              "\"$575,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$475,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 47,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-8: Mega Media Cable TV is able to purchase an exclusive right to sell a premium sports channel in its market area. Let's assume that Mega Media pays $100,000 a year for the exclusive marketing rights to the sports channel. Since Mega Media has already installed cable to all of the homes in its market area, the marginal cost of delivering the sports channel to subscribers is zero. The manager of Mega Media needs to know what price to charge for the sports channel service to maximize her profit. Before setting price, she hires an economist to estimate demand for the sports channel. The economist discovers that there are two types of subscribers who value premium sporting channels. First are the 3,000 die-hard sports fans who will pay as much as $150 a year for the new channel. Second, the premium sports channel will appeal to 20,000 occasional sports viewers who will pay as much as $25 a year for a subscription to it. Refer to Scenario 15-8. How much profit will Mega Media Cable TV earn if it sets the price at $150?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"$350,000\"",
                              "\"$450,000\"",
                              "\"$475,000\"",
                              "\"$575,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$350,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 48,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-8: Mega Media Cable TV is able to purchase an exclusive right to sell a premium sports channel in its market area. Let's assume that Mega Media pays $100,000 a year for the exclusive marketing rights to the sports channel. Since Mega Media has already installed cable to all of the homes in its market area, the marginal cost of delivering the sports channel to subscribers is zero. The manager of Mega Media needs to know what price to charge for the sports channel service to maximize her profit. Before setting price, she hires an economist to estimate demand for the sports channel. The economist discovers that there are two types of subscribers who value premium sporting channels. First are the 3,000 die-hard sports fans who will pay as much as $150 a year for the new channel. Second, the premium sports channel will appeal to 20,000 occasional sports viewers who will pay as much as $25 a year for a subscription to it. Refer to Scenario 15-8. If Mega Media Cable TV is unable to price discriminate, what price will it choose to maximize its profit, and what is the amount of the profit?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"price = $25; profit = $575,000\"",
                              "\"price = $25; profit = $475,000\"",
                              "\"price = $150; profit = $450,000\"",
                              "\"price = $150; profit = $350,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"price = $25; profit = $475,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 49,
                         "topic": "Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Scenario 15-8: Mega Media Cable TV is able to purchase an exclusive right to sell a premium sports channel in its market area. Let's assume that Mega Media pays $100,000 a year for the exclusive marketing rights to the sports channel. Since Mega Media has already installed cable to all of the homes in its market area, the marginal cost of delivering the sports channel to subscribers is zero. The manager of Mega Media needs to know what price to charge for the sports channel service to maximize her profit. Before setting price, she hires an economist to estimate demand for the sports channel. The economist discovers that there are two types of subscribers who value premium sporting channels. First are the 3,000 die-hard sports fans who will pay as much as $150 a year for the new channel. Second, the premium sports channel will appeal to 20,000 occasional sports viewers who will pay as much as $25 a year for a subscription to it. Refer to Scenario 15-8. If Mega Media Cable TV is able to price discriminate, what would be the maximum amount of profit it could generate?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"$950,000\"",
                              "\"$850,000\"",
                              "\"$400,000\"",
                              "\"$350,000\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$850,000\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 50,
                         "topic": "Consumer surplus",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-15. If the monopoly firm is not allowed to price discriminate, then consumer surplus amounts to",
                         "options": [
                              "$0.",
                              "$500.",
                              "\"$1,000.\"",
                              "\"$2,000.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$1,000.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 51,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-15. If the monopoly firm perfectly price discriminates, then consumer surplus amounts to",
                         "options": [
                              "$0.",
                              "$250.",
                              "$500.",
                              "\"$1,000.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "$0.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 52,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-15. If the monopoly firm is not allowed to price discriminate, then the deadweight loss amounts to",
                         "options": [
                              "$50.",
                              "$100.",
                              "$500.",
                              "\"$1,000.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$1,000.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 53,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-15. If the monopoly firm perfectly price discriminates, then the deadweight loss amounts to",
                         "options": [
                              "$0.",
                              "$100.",
                              "$200.",
                              "$500."
                         ],
                         "answer": "$0.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 54,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-15. If there are no fixed costs of production, monopoly profit without price discrimination equals",
                         "options": [
                              "$500.",
                              "\"$1,000.\"",
                              "\"$2,000.\"",
                              "\"$4,000.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$2,000.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 55,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-15. If there are no fixed costs of production, monopoly profit with perfect price discrimination equals",
                         "options": [
                              "$500.",
                              "\"$1,000.\"",
                              "\"$2,000.\"",
                              "\"$4,000.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$4,000.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 56,
                         "topic": "Consumer surplus",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-16. If the monopoly firm is not allowed to price discriminate, then consumer surplus amounts to",
                         "options": [
                              "$0.",
                              "\"$1,562.50.\"",
                              "\"$3,125.\"",
                              "\"$6,250.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$1,562.50.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 57,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-16. If the monopoly firm perfectly price discriminates, then consumer surplus amounts to",
                         "options": [
                              "$0.",
                              "\"$1,562.50.\"",
                              "\"$3,125.\"",
                              "\"$6,250.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "$0.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 58,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-16. If the monopoly firm is not allowed to price discriminate, then the deadweight loss amounts to",
                         "options": [
                              "$0.",
                              "\"$1,562.50.\"",
                              "\"$3,125.\"",
                              "\"$6,250.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$1,562.50.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 59,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-16. If the monopoly firm perfectly price discriminates, then the deadweight loss amounts to",
                         "options": [
                              "$0.",
                              "\"$1,562.50.\"",
                              "\"$3,125.\"",
                              "\"$6,250.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "$0.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 60,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-16. If there are no fixed costs of production, monopoly profit without price discrimination equals",
                         "options": [
                              "$0.",
                              "\"$1,562.50.\"",
                              "\"$3,125.\"",
                              "\"$6,250.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$3,125.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 61,
                         "topic": "Profit",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-16. If there are no fixed costs of production, monopoly profit with perfect price discrimination equals",
                         "options": [
                              "$1.",
                              "\"$1,562.5.\"",
                              "\"$3,125.\"",
                              "\"$6,250.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"$6,250.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 62,
                         "topic": "Consumer surplus",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-17. The consumer surplus at the monopolist’s profit-maximizing price is",
                         "options": [
                              "$450.",
                              "$900.",
                              "\"$1,350.\"",
                              "\"$2,025.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "$450.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 63,
                         "topic": "Deadweight loss",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Refer to Figure 15-17. The deadweight loss caused by a profit-maximizing monopoly amounts to",
                         "options": [
                              "$225.",
                              "$450.",
                              "$900.",
                              "\"$1,350.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "$225.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 64,
                         "topic": "Arbitrage | Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following can defeat the profit-maximizing strategy of price discrimination?",
                         "options": [
                              "consumer surplus",
                              "deadweight loss",
                              "market power",
                              "arbitrage"
                         ],
                         "answer": "arbitrage",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 65,
                         "topic": "Arbitrage | Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Price discrimination is a rational strategy for a profit-maximizing monopolist when",
                         "options": [
                              "the monopolist finds itself able to produce only limited quantities of output.",
                              "consumers are unable to be segmented into identifiable markets.",
                              "the monopolist wishes to increase the deadweight loss that results from profit-maximizing behavior.",
                              "there is no opportunity for arbitrage across market segments."
                         ],
                         "answer": "there is no opportunity for arbitrage across market segments.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 66,
                         "topic": "Arbitrage | Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A market force that can prevent firms from price discriminating is",
                         "options": [
                              "fluctuating resource prices.",
                              "arbitrage.",
                              "high fixed costs.",
                              "marginal-cost pricing."
                         ],
                         "answer": "arbitrage.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 67,
                         "topic": "Arbitrage | Price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The process of buying a good in one market at a low price and selling the good in another market for a higher price in order to profit from the price difference is known as",
                         "options": [
                              "sabotage.",
                              "conspiracy.",
                              "arbitrage.",
                              "collusion."
                         ],
                         "answer": "arbitrage.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 68,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If a monopolist can practice perfect price discrimination, the monopolist will",
                         "options": [
                              "eliminate consumer surplus.",
                              "eliminate deadweight loss.",
                              "maximize profits.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 69,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "options": [
                              "eliminates deadweight loss.",
                              "reduces profits to the monopolist.",
                              "decreases the total quantity sold by the monopolist.",
                              "requires arbitrage in order for the monopolist to maximize profits."
                         ],
                         "answer": "eliminates deadweight loss.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 70,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "options": [
                              "increases profits to the firm.",
                              "increases total surplus.",
                              "decreases consumer surplus.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 71,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A perfectly price-discriminating monopolist is able to",
                         "options": [
                              "maximize profit and produce a socially-optimal level of output.",
                              "\"maximize profit, but not produce a socially-optimal level of output.\"",
                              "\"produce a socially-optimal level of output, but not maximize profit.\"",
                              "exercise illegal preferences regarding the race and/or gender of its employees."
                         ],
                         "answer": "maximize profit and produce a socially-optimal level of output.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 72,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If a monopolist is able to perfectly price discriminate,",
                         "options": [
                              "consumer surplus is always increased.",
                              "total surplus is always decreased.",
                              "consumer surplus and deadweight losses are transformed into monopoly profits.",
                              "the price effect dominates the output effect on monopoly revenue."
                         ],
                         "answer": "consumer surplus and deadweight losses are transformed into monopoly profits.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 73,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "In theory, perfect price discrimination",
                         "options": [
                              "decreases the monopolist's profits.",
                              "decreases consumer surplus.",
                              "increases deadweight loss.",
                              "reduces the number of consumers who purchase the monopoly’s product."
                         ],
                         "answer": "decreases consumer surplus.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 74,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Perfect price discrimination describes a situation in which the monopolist",
                         "options": [
                              "knows the exact willingness to pay of each of its customers.",
                              "charges exactly two different prices to exactly two different groups of customers.",
                              "maximizes consumer surplus.",
                              "experiences a zero economic profit."
                         ],
                         "answer": "knows the exact willingness to pay of each of its customers.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 75,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "In reality, perfect price discrimination is",
                         "options": [
                              "used by about 75 percent of all monopolies.",
                              "used by about 50 percent of all monopolies.",
                              "seldom used by monopolies because it leads to lower profits.",
                              "rarely possible."
                         ],
                         "answer": "rarely possible.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 76,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "How does a competitive market compare to a monopoly that engages in perfect price discrimination?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"In both cases, total social welfare is the same.\"",
                              "Total social welfare is higher in the competitive market than with the perfectly price discriminating monopoly.",
                              "\"In both cases, some potentially mutually beneficial trades do not occur.\"",
                              "Consumer surplus is the same in both cases."
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"In both cases, total social welfare is the same.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 77,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopolist that practices perfect price discrimination",
                         "options": [
                              "creates no deadweight loss.",
                              "\"charges one group of buyers a higher price than another group, such as offering a student discount.\"",
                              "charges a higher price but produces the same monopoly level of output as when a single price is charged.",
                              "charges some customers a price below marginal cost because costs are covered by the high-priced buyers."
                         ],
                         "answer": "creates no deadweight loss.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 78,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "A monopolist faces the following demand curve:\n\nPrice,Quantity\n$8,300\n$7,400\n$6,500\n$5,600\n$4,700\n$3,800\n$2,900\n$1,\"1,000\"\n\nThe monopolist has fixed costs of $1,000 and has a constant marginal cost of $2 per unit. If the monopolist were able to perfectly price discriminate, how many units would it sell?",
                         "options": [
                              "400",
                              "500",
                              "900",
                              "\"4,200\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "900",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 79,
                         "topic": "Perfect price discrimination",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "With perfect price discrimination the monopoly",
                         "options": [
                              "eliminates all price discrimination by charging each customer the same price.",
                              "charges each customer an amount equal to the monopolist's marginal cost of production.",
                              "eliminates deadweight loss.",
                              "eliminates profits and increases consumer surplus."
                         ],
                         "answer": "eliminates deadweight loss.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 80,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following is not one of the ways that antitrust laws promote competition?",
                         "options": [
                              "Antitrust laws allow the government to prevent mergers.",
                              "Antitrust laws allow the government to break up companies into smaller ones.",
                              "Antitrust laws prevent companies from coordinating their activities in ways that make markets less competitive.",
                              "Antitrust laws allow the government to shut down any firm the government believes has monopoly power."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Antitrust laws allow the government to shut down any firm the government believes has monopoly power.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    }
               ]
          },
          "sector6": {
               "title": "PUBLIC POLICY TOWARD MONOPOLIES",
               "questions": [
                    {
                         "q_num": 1,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following is the preferred strategy for the government to follow to remedy the inefficient allocation of resources associated with monopolies?",
                         "options": [
                              "preventing mergers through antitrust laws",
                              "regulating the prices that monopolies can charge",
                              "doing nothing",
                              "None of the above strategies is preferred. Each is a viable strategy."
                         ],
                         "answer": "None of the above strategies is preferred. Each is a viable strategy.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 2,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "The government may use antitrust laws to break up an existing company to improve competition.",
                              "The government may break up a natural monopoly to lower the price charged to customers.",
                              "Private ownership is typically preferred to public ownership.",
                              "Sometimes the best strategy is for the government to do nothing about monopoly inefficiency because the “fix” may be worse than the problem."
                         ],
                         "answer": "The government may break up a natural monopoly to lower the price charged to customers.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 3,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "The government may use antitrust laws to prevent a merger if the government believes the merger will reduce competition and increase prices.",
                              "\"By regulating a natural monopoly where price equals average total cost, the monopoly earns zero profits.\"",
                              "An advantage of private ownership over public ownership is that private business owners tend to fire inefficient managers.",
                              "The government should always intervene to improve monopoly inefficiency."
                         ],
                         "answer": "The government should always intervene to improve monopoly inefficiency.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 4,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following may eliminate some or all of the inefficiency that results from monopoly pricing?",
                         "options": [
                              "The government can regulate the monopoly.",
                              "The monopoly can be prohibited from price discriminating.",
                              "The monopoly can be forced to operate at a point where its marginal revenue is equal to its marginal cost.",
                              "None of the above would eliminate any inefficiency associated with a monopoly."
                         ],
                         "answer": "The government can regulate the monopoly.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 5,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Antitrust laws have economic benefits that outweigh the costs if they",
                         "options": [
                              "prevent mergers that would decrease competition and lower the costs of production.",
                              "prevent mergers that would decrease competition and raise the costs of production.",
                              "allow mergers that would decrease competition and raise the costs of production.",
                              "None of the above is correct because antitrust laws never have economic benefits that outweigh the costs."
                         ],
                         "answer": "prevent mergers that would decrease competition and raise the costs of production.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 6,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "Two examples of early antitrust laws are the Sherman and Clayton Antitrust Acts.",
                              "Antitrust laws automatically prevent mergers between companies that produce similar products.",
                              "Antitrust laws give the government power to increase competition.",
                              "Antitrust laws can reduce social welfare if they prevent mergers that would lower costs through more efficient joint production."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Antitrust laws automatically prevent mergers between companies that produce similar products.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 7,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "Two examples of early antitrust laws are the Clinton and Stigler Antitrust Acts.",
                              "Antitrust laws automatically prevent mergers between companies that produce similar products.",
                              "Antitrust laws reduce the government’s power to regulate private companies.",
                              "Antitrust laws can reduce social welfare if they prevent mergers that would lower costs through more efficient joint production."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Antitrust laws can reduce social welfare if they prevent mergers that would lower costs through more efficient joint production.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 8,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The first major piece of antitrust legislation was the",
                         "options": [
                              "Clayton Act.",
                              "Reagan-Bush Act.",
                              "Sherman Act.",
                              "Clinton-Gore Act."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Sherman Act.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 9,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The legislation passed by Congress in 1890 to reduce the market power of large and powerful \"trusts\" was the",
                         "options": [
                              "Morgan Act.",
                              "Sherman Act.",
                              "Clayton Act.",
                              "14th Amendment."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Sherman Act.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 10,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The legislation passed by Congress in 1914 to strengthen the government’s powers and authorize private lawsuits was the",
                         "options": [
                              "Morgan Act.",
                              "Sherman Act.",
                              "Clayton Act.",
                              "14th Amendment."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Clayton Act.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 11,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The collection of statutes aimed at curbing monopoly power is called",
                         "options": [
                              "the 14th amendment.",
                              "the Clayton Act.",
                              "the Sherman Act.",
                              "antitrust law."
                         ],
                         "answer": "antitrust law.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 12,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "In order for antitrust laws to raise social welfare, the government must",
                         "options": [
                              "disallow synergy benefits from accruing to monopolists.",
                              "disallow any mergers from taking place.",
                              "be able to determine which mergers are desirable and which are not.",
                              "always attempt to keep markets in their most competitive form."
                         ],
                         "answer": "be able to determine which mergers are desirable and which are not.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 13,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Reduced competition through merging of companies will raise social welfare",
                         "options": [
                              "if the social cost from the synergies exceeds the benefit of increased market power.",
                              "if the benefit from the synergies exceeds the social cost of increased market power.",
                              "always.",
                              "never."
                         ],
                         "answer": "if the benefit from the synergies exceeds the social cost of increased market power.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 14,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "One method used to control the ability of firms to capture monopoly profit in the United States is through",
                         "options": [
                              "government purchase of products produced by monopolists.",
                              "government distribution of a monopolist's excess production.",
                              "enforcement of antitrust laws.",
                              "regulation of firms in highly competitive markets."
                         ],
                         "answer": "enforcement of antitrust laws.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 15,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Antitrust laws may",
                         "options": [
                              "enhance the ability of firms to capture profits from a concentration of market power.",
                              "enhance the ability of firms to reduce economic losses.",
                              "restrict the ability of firms to operate at the socially efficient level of production.",
                              "restrict the ability of firms to merge."
                         ],
                         "answer": "restrict the ability of firms to merge.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 16,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Antitrust laws allow the government to",
                         "options": [
                              "prevent mergers.",
                              "break up companies.",
                              "promote competition.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 17,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Antitrust laws allow the government to",
                         "options": [
                              "collect revenues through the antitrust tax.",
                              "break up companies.",
                              "purchase privately-held companies through eminent domain.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "break up companies.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 18,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Splitting up a monopoly is often justified on the grounds that",
                         "options": [
                              "consumers prefer dealing with small firms.",
                              "small firms have lower costs.",
                              "competition is inherently efficient.",
                              "small firms produce higher quality products."
                         ],
                         "answer": "competition is inherently efficient.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 19,
                         "topic": "Antitrust",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Antitrust laws",
                         "options": [
                              "prevent firms from maximizing profits.",
                              "\"allow the government to prevent mergers, even ones that would benefit consumers.\"",
                              "require the government to measure both the benefits and costs of a potential merger.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"allow the government to prevent mergers, even ones that would benefit consumers.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 20,
                         "topic": "Antitrust  | Regulation  | Public ownership",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "Public ownership is preferred to regulation in order to minimize the deadweight losses associated with natural monopolies.",
                              "Antitrust laws are always the best way to limit monopoly power.",
                              "It is possible that the best approach to monopolies is for the government to do nothing.",
                              "Marginal-cost pricing requires a natural monopoly to earn zero economic profits."
                         ],
                         "answer": "It is possible that the best approach to monopolies is for the government to do nothing.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 21,
                         "topic": "Antitrust | Regulation | Public ownership",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following is not correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "Antitrust laws may prevent mergers that would actually raise social welfare.",
                              "Public ownership is the most common public policy toward monopolies in the United States.",
                              "Regulation is a common strategy for a natural monopoly.",
                              "Sometimes the best public policy toward a monopoly may be to do nothing."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Public ownership is the most common public policy toward monopolies in the United States.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 22,
                         "topic": "Antitrust  | Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "Part of the deadweight loss associated with monopoly is measured by the monopolist's economic profit.",
                              "Marginal cost is always less than average total cost in a natural monopoly.",
                              "Discount coupons available free to the public are a type of price discrimination.",
                              "Anti-trust laws make it harder for firms to create synergies."
                         ],
                         "answer": "Part of the deadweight loss associated with monopoly is measured by the monopolist's economic profit.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 23,
                         "topic": "Regulation",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "One problem with government operation of monopolies is that",
                         "options": [
                              "a benevolent government is likely to be interested in generating profits for political gain.",
                              "monopolies typically have rising average costs.",
                              "the government typically has little incentive to reduce costs.",
                              "a government-regulated outcome will increase the profitability of the monopoly."
                         ],
                         "answer": "the government typically has little incentive to reduce costs.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 24,
                         "topic": "Regulation",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "One problem with regulating a monopolist on the basis of cost is that",
                         "options": [
                              "\"by focusing on costs, the regulators ignore profits.\"",
                              "it does not provide an incentive for the monopolist to reduce its cost.",
                              "\"a monopolist's costs, by definition, are higher than costs of perfectly competitive firms.\"",
                              "a monopolist is still able to generate excessive economic profits."
                         ],
                         "answer": "it does not provide an incentive for the monopolist to reduce its cost.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 25,
                         "topic": "Regulation",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The task of economic regulation is to",
                         "options": [
                              "protect monopoly profits.",
                              "approximate the results of the competitive market.",
                              "replace competition with government ownership.",
                              "increase competition within the market."
                         ],
                         "answer": "approximate the results of the competitive market.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 26,
                         "topic": "Regulation  | Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If government regulation sets the maximum price for a natural monopoly equal to its marginal cost, then the natural monopolist will",
                         "options": [
                              "earn economic losses.",
                              "earn economic profits.",
                              "earn zero economic profits.",
                              "produce a lower quantity of output than is socially optimal."
                         ],
                         "answer": "earn economic losses.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 27,
                         "topic": "Regulation  | Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If the government regulates the price that a natural monopolist can charge to be equal to the firm’s marginal cost, the firm will",
                         "options": [
                              "earn zero profits.",
                              "\"earn positive profits, causing other firms to enter the industry.\"",
                              "\"earn negative profits, causing the firm to exit the industry.\"",
                              "minimize costs in order to lower the price that it charges."
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"earn negative profits, causing the firm to exit the industry.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 28,
                         "topic": "Regulation  | Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "If the government regulates the price that a natural monopolist can charge to be equal to the firm’s average total cost, the firm will",
                         "options": [
                              "earn zero profits.",
                              "\"earn positive profits, causing other firms to enter the industry.\"",
                              "\"earn negative profits, causing the firm to exit the industry.\"",
                              "minimize costs in order to lower the price that it charges."
                         ],
                         "answer": "earn zero profits.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 29,
                         "topic": "Regulation  | Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "When regulators use a marginal-cost pricing strategy to regulate a natural monopoly, the regulated monopoly",
                         "options": [
                              "will experience a loss.",
                              "will experience a price below average total cost.",
                              "may rely on a government subsidy to remain in business.",
                              "All of the above are correct."
                         ],
                         "answer": "All of the above are correct.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 30,
                         "topic": "Regulation  | Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Since natural monopolies have a declining average cost curve, regulating natural monopolies by setting price equal to marginal cost would",
                         "options": [
                              "cause the monopolist to operate at a loss.",
                              "result in a less than optimal total surplus.",
                              "maximize producer surplus.",
                              "result in higher profits for the monopoly."
                         ],
                         "answer": "cause the monopolist to operate at a loss.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 31,
                         "topic": "Public ownership  | Regulation",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Policymakers are discussing various proposals regarding how to deal with natural monopolies. Senator Huff wants to regulate natural monopolies by equating price with average total cost. Huff contends that such a policy will ensure that monopolies make every effort to reduce costs. Senator Puff wants the government to own natural monopolies. Puff argues that government-owned monopolies usually do a better job of holding down costs than privately owned monopolies. Which senator's argument is correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "Senator Huff",
                              "Senator Puff",
                              "both senators",
                              "neither senator"
                         ],
                         "answer": "neither senator",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 32,
                         "topic": "Public ownership",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which type of public policy toward monopolies is much more common in Europe than in the United States?",
                         "options": [
                              "antitrust laws",
                              "regulation",
                              "public ownership",
                              "“do nothing”"
                         ],
                         "answer": "public ownership",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 33,
                         "topic": "Public ownership",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following is an example of public ownership of a monopoly?",
                         "options": [
                              "DeBeers",
                              "Microsoft",
                              "U.S. Postal Service",
                              "AT&T"
                         ],
                         "answer": "U.S. Postal Service",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 34,
                         "topic": "Public ownership",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Private ownership of a monopoly may benefit society because the monopoly will have an incentive to",
                         "options": [
                              "charge a price that is consistent with that of a benevolent social planner.",
                              "charge a price that prevents some people from buying.",
                              "price its good according to the intersection of marginal cost and average revenue.",
                              "lower its costs to earn a higher profit."
                         ],
                         "answer": "lower its costs to earn a higher profit.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 35,
                         "topic": "Public ownership  | Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The key issue in determining the efficiency of public versus private ownership of a monopoly is",
                         "options": [
                              "the tendency for efficient management of publicly owned enterprises.",
                              "the inability of private monopolies to get rid of managers that are doing a bad job.",
                              "the propensity of private monopolies to generate excessive profits.",
                              "how ownership of the firm affects the cost of production."
                         ],
                         "answer": "how ownership of the firm affects the cost of production.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 36,
                         "topic": "Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a typical natural monopoly, average total cost is",
                         "options": [
                              "\"falling, and marginal cost is above average total cost.\"",
                              "\"falling, and marginal cost is below average total cost.\"",
                              "\"rising, and marginal cost is below average total cost.\"",
                              "\"rising, and marginal cost is above average total cost.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"falling, and marginal cost is below average total cost.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 37,
                         "topic": "Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "In the majority of cases where there is a natural monopoly in the United States, the government usually deals with the problem",
                         "options": [
                              "by splitting the natural monopoly into smaller companies.",
                              "through regulation.",
                              "by turning the natural monopoly into a public enterprise.",
                              "by doing nothing."
                         ],
                         "answer": "through regulation.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 38,
                         "topic": "Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "In a natural monopoly,",
                         "options": [
                              "society would be better off if antitrust laws were used to create many different firms in the market.",
                              "the marginal cost curve is positively sloped.",
                              "\"if the government requires marginal cost pricing, it will likely have to subsidize the firm.\"",
                              "the marginal revenue curve is horizontal."
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"if the government requires marginal cost pricing, it will likely have to subsidize the firm.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 39,
                         "topic": "Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "For a long while, electricity producers were thought to be a classic example of a natural monopoly. People held this view because",
                         "options": [
                              "the average cost of producing units of electricity by one producer in a specific region was lower than if the same quantity were produced by two or more producers in the same region.",
                              "the average cost of producing units of electricity by one producer in a specific region was higher than if the same quantity were produced by two or more produced in the same region.",
                              "the marginal cost of producing units of electricity by one producer in a specific region was higher than if the same quantity were produced by two or more producers in the same region.",
                              "electricity is a special non-excludable good that could never be sold in a competitive market."
                         ],
                         "answer": "the average cost of producing units of electricity by one producer in a specific region was lower than if the same quantity were produced by two or more producers in the same region.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 40,
                         "topic": "Natural monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The reason to regulate utilities instead of using antitrust laws to promote competition is that a utility is usually a",
                         "options": [
                              "profit-maximizing monopoly.",
                              "producer of externalities.",
                              "revenue-maximizing monopoly.",
                              "natural monopoly."
                         ],
                         "answer": "natural monopoly.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 41,
                         "topic": "Do nothing",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The assessment by George Stigler concerning the tradeoffs between \"market failure\" and \"political failure\" in the American economy provides support for which of the following solutions to the problems of monopolies?",
                         "options": [
                              "public ownership of monopolies",
                              "government regulation of monopolies",
                              "government incentives to promote competition in monopolized industries",
                              "doing nothing at all"
                         ],
                         "answer": "doing nothing at all",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 42,
                         "topic": "Do nothing",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "The George Stigler quote, “...the degree of ‘market failure’ for the American economy is much smaller than the ‘political failure’ arising from the imperfections of economic policies ...” illustrates the advantage of which type of public policy toward monopolies?",
                         "options": [
                              "antitrust laws",
                              "regulation",
                              "public ownership",
                              "“do nothing”"
                         ],
                         "answer": "“do nothing”",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 1,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following strategies is not an effective strategy to reduce monopoly inefficiency?",
                         "options": [
                              "antitrust laws",
                              "price discrimination",
                              "doing nothing",
                              "breaking up a natural monopoly into more than one firm"
                         ],
                         "answer": "breaking up a natural monopoly into more than one firm",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 2,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Most firms have",
                         "options": [
                              "no monopoly pricing power.",
                              "some monopoly pricing power.",
                              "absolute monopoly pricing power.",
                              "the ability to earn monopoly profits."
                         ],
                         "answer": "some monopoly pricing power.",
                         "explanation": ""
                    },
                    {
                         "q_num": 3,
                         "topic": "Monopoly",
                         "type": "mcq",
                         "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
                         "options": [
                              "\"Firms with some degree of monopoly power are common, but firms with substantial monopoly power are rare.\"",
                              "\"Firms with some degree of monopoly power are rare, as are firms with substantial monopoly power.\"",
                              "\"Firms with some degree of monopoly power are common, as are firms with substantial monopoly power.\"",
                              "\"Firms with some degree of monopoly power are rare, but firms with substantial monopoly power are common.\""
                         ],
                         "answer": "\"Firms with some degree of monopoly power are common, but firms with substantial monopoly power are rare.\"",
                         "explanation": ""
                    }
               ]
          }
     }
}
